- [ambulance siren wailing]
- [man 1] I got his feet. Get his head.
[man 2] He's bleeding from the right side
of his head! Breathing is shallow!
[man 3] Copy that!
- We found no dangerous objects.
- [man 4] Understood! Step aside!
[man 3] Excuse me.
Everyone, please stand back.
- [indistinct yelling]
- [whistle blowing]
- [man 1] EMTs have arrived!
- [man 2] Help is here!
[man 1] All right. Let's rescue them.
[man 3] 25, 26, 27, 28, 29, 30. Okay!
[monitor flatlining]
[man 3] Stopping CPR.
Beginning ECG analysis.
[alarm ringing]
Monitor VF.
- Get ready.
- [defibrillator charging]
- All clear!
- [both] All clear!
- Activate it!
- [man 4] Yes, sir!
[defibrillating]
[man 5] Still flatlining!
[man 3] Get him in the ambulance.
Positions!
[both] Sir.
[men] One, two, three!
- What the hell is going on?
- [man] One, two, three!
[girl] Yusuke!
- [girl crying]
- [whistle blowing]
Yusuke!
- It's not safe here! You have to leave!
- Yusuke!
- Hey, listen to me! Wait!
- Please stay back!
- This is your friend?
- What's going on?
- Yes.
- Understood.
- Yusuke!
- Hey!
- [man 1] She says she knows him.
- [man 2] I see. This way.
- Listen to me! I said hold on!
- [girl] Yusuke! Yusuke!
- Hey! Listen!
- [girl] Yusuke!
Watch the door!
SARAYASHIKI CITY FIRE DEPARTMENT
Son of a bitch…
[man on radio] …six,
you may now proceed.
Paramedics are on the scene.
Proceed with caution.
Clear a route to the hospital…
Wait, am I dead?
4 HOURS AGO
[dramatic music playing]
[wings fluttering]
[girl] I can't believe
you're on the roof smoking again.
What are you doing skipping class?
Keiko, seriously, would you quit snooping?
Why are you even here?
[Keiko] I'm not snooping, you idiot.
- The teacher's looking for you right now.
- [exhales]
They want to give me another lecture?
Don't worry about it, okay?
Stop it! [grunts]
I get in trouble too.
They know we've been friends
since we were little.
[inhales sharply]
I just have to go down there, yeah?
I get it.
[sighing]
Oh brother!
[door opens]
[door closes]
[indistinct chatter]
Kirino!
Hey.
[chuckling nervously]
[boy 1 laughing]
- [grunts]
- [boy 2] Look out!
- [laughing] Oh!
[grunting]
- [boy 3] You know this isn't enough.
- [Kirino grunts]
- There it is.
- Oh.
[grunting]
[man] Hey!
What are you doing?
You delinquent.
Extortion is a new low.
Huh?
- [grunting] Uh, uh… No, he--
- [whispers] Shut up.
[man] Dirtbags like you
are a menace to society!
This school doesn't need trash like you!
Shut it. I'll do what I want.
[man grunting]
[man] Urameshi!
[man grunts]
The rest of you, get back to class!
[thrumming]
[tense music playing]
- [birds chirping]
- [dog barking in distance]
[lighter clicking]
[sighing]
[woman on TV] Sakyo, I understand you're
working on a new business venture,
using the casino's profits
to give back to the city.
[Sakyo] That's right. The sinkhole
has been there for many years,
now it can finally serve the city.
The sinkhole is a symbol
of Sarayashiki City.
Soon, it will be an entertainment venue.
I think the good people of this city
deserve a little amusement, don't you?
The world needs something new. [chuckling]
[woman on TV laughing]
So, in terms of implementing
this new business venture,
what is your long-term strategy…
Yusuke, no school today?
I got angry so I ditched.
You can make me coffee
since you skipped class.
Okay, okay.
Why even go? Nobody's making you.
It's not easy for a single mom
to earn your tuition.
And now, I'm getting a lecture
from my own mother.
- That's great.
- [mom] Don't want a lecture?
Try acting like an adult
instead of a freeloader.
Yeah, yeah.
[sighing] Guess today's
just my unlucky day.
Urameshi!
[upbeat song playing]
You don't quit, Kuwabara.
I thought we settled this yesterday.
Shut it!
Yesterday, you just got lucky.
Today's a new day.
I'm gonna take you down!
Look, I'm pretty angry right now.
Sure you wanna do this?
[men screaming, groaning]
[upbeat song continues]
Calm down, Kuwabara!
[all yelling]
[loud thudding]
[all grunting]
[grunting, groaning]
- Let's let him off the hook for now!
- Shut it!
[yelps]
[grunting]
[Kuwabara grunting]
[men groaning]
Kuwa… Kuwabara!
[Kuwabara] I'm not done yet.
[grunting]
Wow, you don't quit.
[grunting aggressively]
[grunting, panting]
- [friend 1] Kuwabara!
- [friend 2] Kuwabara!
- [friend 1] Are you okay?
- [friend 3] Kuwabara!
- Let's leave it at that for now.
- [friend 3] Let's go home.
The real battle's about to start.
You put up a great fight! Let's go!
[Kuwabara] This is a fight between rivals.
Kuwabara, Yusuke left.
See? He's already gone.
[song ends]
[panting]
[laughs]
- [Kuwabara grunts]
- Oh! Kuwabara!
[Kuwabara exhales]
[indistinct chatter]
WELCOME TO YUKIMURA DINER
Thank you, sir!
[boy] Let's go, Masaru!
Yeah!
[woman] Welcome!
- [man] Welcome!
- [Yusuke] Ramen!
- [woman] One Ramen!
- [man] One Ramen coming up!
SARAYASHIKI CITY SHOPPING ARCADE
- [man 1] I'm sorry.
- [man 2] Sorry, sir.
- Saying sorry doesn't fix anything.
- I understand, sir.
Sorry, but we'll let
everybody through eventually.
- Where are they now?
- Everyone's stuck here.
- How long until we move this along?
- [horns honking]
- [music playing on radio]
Geez. [sighing]
What the hell's going on now?
I've been sitting here forever.
We've all got things to do. Let's go!
[groans]
What a bunch of idiots out there!
[sighing]
[groans]
Let's go. While we're still young.
[exhaling deeply] Oh, come--
[grunting, groaning]
[dramatic music playing]
[tires screeching]
- [engine revving]
- [grunts]
- [horn blaring]
- [tires squealing]
[brakes screeching]
[tires screeching]
[engine revving]
[girls laughing]
- Hey! I'm back!
- [woman] Hi! Welcome back!
- Hi…
- [man] Hello!
- [woman] Welcome.
- [man] Ah. There she is!
- Wait, wait. Hold on.
- [man] You hungry?
- [Yusuke slurping]
- Look… Keiko.
- [Keiko] Huh?
- Uh, we're gonna go.
Huh? No, but--
I'm sorry. Bye, Keiko!
See ya!
Wait.
[grunting] Huh?
[man 1 laughing]
You're unbelievable as always.
[man 2 laughing]
- I'm telling you.
- [man 1 laughing]
Hey, Yusuke!
Yeah? What?
Today, at school,
you stopped the bullies, right?
Why didn't you explain
you were helping another student?
No way. That's too much effort.
Yusuke, why don't you
listen to me for once?
I'm telling you, I'll handle this.
- [slurping]
- Whatever.
All right. Well, I don't care.
Oh, great. That's good.
See ya later, detective.
Quit calling me that!
Just go and… Go die!
[door closes]
[children screaming]
[woman] Welcome back.
[loud banging]
- [man] Hey, what's that?
- [crashing]
[people shouting, screaming]
[dramatic music playing]
[growling]
[people screaming]
[driver growling]
[people yelling]
[screaming]
- [people continue screaming]
- [music continues]
[engine revving]
[brakes squealing]
[theme music playing]
[narrator] Long ago,
the Human World and Demon World
were connected.
Humans who wandered into the Demon World
were attacked by yokai,
while yokai crept into the Human World
to prey on humans.
Later, the Spirit World drew a boundary
between the two,
separating the Human World
from the Demon World.
- Or at least, that was the plan.
- [man 1] Let's bring him down.
- Nice and easy.
- [fluttering]
[siren wailing]
[man 2] Okay! Cleared! Okay, all cleared!
Yes! You understand? You got it?
Wow. Looks like I'm a ghost now.
How impressive! Kids these days
are pretty quick to catch on.
[man] Check the parameter.
A lot of victims of accidents can't accept
that they are in the afterlife now.
So, this is enough evidence
to convince you of that. Right?
[man] Coming through!
Who would you be?
Think of me as your guide.
Botan at your service.
They say "Grim Reaper" in the West.
I have many titles.
- Greetings!
- Screw your greetings! This is crazy!
- I guess you're still feeling bad, right?
- Yeah! Obviously!
I'm in shock. Can't you tell?
Why don't you get that smile
off your face, you little punk?
Oh. Of course.
Yes, your personality matches the data.
Urameshi, 17 years old.
First name, Yusuke.
Rough, violent, and reckless.
- Shut it!
- Not very intelligent and Ill-tempered.
Fighting, drinking, gambling…
- [gasps] Quite a reputation.
- You got a complaint?
- It might be a good thing you died.
- You wanna fight, scumbag?
'Cause it sounds like you're really evil.
[Yusuke] Shut up! Leave me alone!
[Botan] Where are you going?
I haven't finished.
[doctor] His forehead and hands
are a little grazed,
but there are no fractures,
and his brain is completely fine.
[sighs] Oh, thank goodness!
Isn't that great, Masaru?
So that means there's no need
for him to be hospitalized.
He can go home today.
Okay. Uh…
Doctor, can you tell us what happened
to that student who saved my son?
[sighs]
I guess… [sighing]
…that's enough.
Botan, is that right?
[inhales deeply]
You can take me away now.
To hell, or wherever.
[inhales, groans]
[chuckles]
You know, appearances can be deceiving.
I don't think you understand.
I'm not bringing you to hell
or anywhere for that matter.
Huh? What are you saying?
To tell you the truth,
your death was not anticipated
by the Spirit World.
Nobody could have ever imagined
a hoodlum like you
would have sacrificed himself
in order to save a child.
Oddities like this are very rare.
Did you say odd?
There are important things
that we still have to discuss, Yusuke.
But first we have to get you
to the Spirit World.
Don't worry.
My boss will explain everything.
- We're leaving?
- [Botan] Yes.
Right now.
Wh-- What is this?
[Botan] The Spirit World is on
a higher plane than the third dimension.
I don't understand.
Just think of it as a mysterious world.
[ethereal music playing]
[Yusuke grunts]
[ethereal music continues]
See there? That's where the boss is.
Tell me,
who exactly is this boss of yours?
My boss is Enma, of course.
Wha-- Really? Enma?
How about that.
[ethereal music continues]
[scrolls thudding]
[baby crying]
[whizzing]
Wanna play?
Thanks.
Does it hurt?
No.
Thank you.
[man] Here you go.
In that case, thank you.
Thank you so much.
[man] Are you okay?
- Thank you.
- [man] Not at all.
Thank you so much. Thank you very much.
- Of course.
- Uh, thanks.
[whizzing]
[whooshing]
Hi there.
- I brought Yusuke Urameshi.
- [Enma] Ah.
I'm almost done. Give me a minute.
- [man] Come back, you damn kids!
- Shut up, you old dinosaur!
- [boy 1] Run, quickly!
- [boy 2] Quickly, go!
[man] You little brats!
What's he doing?
[Botan] He's dividing the souls
of the dead between heaven and hell.
[man] Give me that!
[Yusuke] Wow. The process
sure is different from what I've heard.
[Botan] The process has changed a lot.
See, over the years, we've worked hard
to increase efficiency in how we work.
[man] Dammit! [yelling]
[whizzing]
[whooshing]
[Enma] How do you do?
Welcome.
You're
Enma?
I am King Enma Jr., also known as Koenma.
So you need to watch your tongue.
What was that?
No! [shushing]
Never mind.
[inhales deeply]
As you can see, I'm so busy I could die.
So, I'll cut to the chase.
Listen up, Yusuke Urameshi.
I'm resurrecting you.
In exchange,
you'll work as a Spirit Detective.
And what's that?
Well, you'll be solving cases
involving yokai
that have invaded the Human World.
That role has been vacant
for quite a while now, unfortunately.
And there's trouble in the world.
[rumbling]
This is a yokai
called a roundworm monster.
They usually inhabit the Demon World,
but they seem
to have entered the Human World.
Find out why the roundworm monster
has appeared in the Human World.
And you'll be alive again.
That's incentive enough.
[pensive music playing]
No, thanks.
Huh?
Huh? You're getting a second chance.
Why would you refuse that?
I don't like being told what to do.
Plus, everyone will be relieved
that Yusuke's dead.
See ya.
[somber music playing]
Wa-- Wait a minute now.
[Enma] Huh?
[somber music playing]
[music continues]
[sighs]
[wind whooshing]
[intense music playing]
[arcade game machines dinging]
- That was fun.
- Mm-hmm.
- Let's try that!
- Yeah!
[intense music continues]
- [dealer] It's a draw!
- [man] Yes!
Tarukane is here at the roulette table.
- This one.
- [woman] Yeah? [chuckles]
Are you enjoying yourself
at my casino, Tarukane?
I've lost 200 million yen.
Why not try putting
everything you have left on 22?
- [dealer] Last call.
- [Tarukane] Hmm.
[bell dings]
[dealer] No more bets.
- Winning number, 22, black. Even.
- Huh?
[woman gasps] Really?
- [man] Congratulations.
- [women squeal, laugh]
[Tarukane] Ah.
So it's been rigged, huh?
Of course not.
- [scoffs]
- You don't believe it?
By the way, I heard you're trying
to start a new business
with that sinkhole we sold you.
Yes.
You heard correctly.
You're the only person obsessing
over that big hole in the ground.
[scoffs]
Did you find buried treasure down there?
No.
No. Something even better.
[intriguing music playing]
A hole that goes on and on.
And it leads right to the Demon World.
[dealer] Paying the winner.
Congratulations, sir!
- [women laughing]
- [woman] Congratulations!
[man] Whoa! I won!
[Botan] You're very sentimental
for a 17-year-old.
[siren wailing in distance]
Botan, please go.
You really don't want to be alive?
I've done this sort of thing
for a while now, Yusuke.
The best way for you to tell
what everyone thinks of the deceased
is when they come to pay their respects.
Think about what you want to do.
How about we visit your wake?
- [rhythmic drumming]
- [monk chanting]
[man] Okay, next!
[indistinct chatter]
- You hungry?
- I'm thinking ramen today.
[boy] Sounds good.
Either that or Chinese soba.
- That's the same thing, right?
- [boys laugh]
- This looks about right.
- [boy 1] Oh!
[boy 2] Kirino! Perfect timing!
What you got there?
- [gasps]
- Hand it over, now.
You're an idiot.
Why would you give cash to some dead guy?
[boys laughing]
Bunch of stupid assholes.
A condolence gift.
[laughing]
- No!
- Oh!
- Easy there! Come on!
- Give it back here!
[grunting]
No! Don't! [sobbing]
[grunts]
You worthless loser.
Hey! Stop, stop, Kuwabara! This is a wake!
- Stop him! Stop!
- Hey…
- [all grunting]
- Let go! Hey! Let go!
[grunting]
Urameshi, you bastard!
Dying before our rematch
is a sleazy tactic!
[hyperventilating]
You should still be alive!
Kuwabara!
- Oh, sorry!
- [whimpering]
Please! Just one more round!
Let go! [grunting]
That moron's here too.
- [Kuwabara] Let go!
- [friend] Let's just calm him down.
It's okay.
- [rhythmic drumming]
- [chanting]
Thank you for saving my life!
Hey, Mommy.
Let's talk to him once he's awake, okay?
Then I can also say thank you
face-to-face! Isn't that right?
- [somber music playing]
- [chanting continues]
[drumming, chanting fades]
[somber music continues]
[woman] We've done this before.
[Keiko] Hmm?
You don't recall?
When Yusuke caught a cold.
- Oh…
- [chuckles]
Middle of winter,
my son dives into the river.
[chuckles]
That's right. I remember.
He dove after my hat.
- [chuckles]
- That's right.
That may have been the only time
he caught a cold.
Who could forget something like that?
[laughs] I was so worried that day.
Mmm.
That time, too…
you cared for him and never left his side.
Right, Keiko?
[inhales deeply]
This is my fault, Atsuko.
Atsuko,
I…
I was angry at Yusuke that day.
I… I told Yusuke to go die.
[sobbing]
Even though I didn't mean it. Still…
[continues sobbing]
It's all my fault.
[sobbing]
I'm sorry!
I'm so sorry.
Atsuko.
Yusuke… [sobbing]
[both sobbing]
It's all right.
Don't worry. That kind of thing
wouldn't bother Yusuke.
So don't make that face.
He would hate to see it.
[both sobbing]
He's made two grown women cry in one go.
He's so annoying!
[sobbing]
- [somber music continues]
- [both continue sobbing]
[music ends]
- [boy 1] Hey! Hey, hey, hey!
- [Kirino grunting]
Nice one!
Go, go, go, go!
- [boy 1] Oh!
- [boy 2] Go, go, go, go!
- [indistinct chatter and laughter]
- [grunting]
[boy 1] Hey!
- [boy 2] One more!
- [panting]
- [boy 3] Yeah! Get him!
- [boy laughing]
Whoa, hey, hey, hey!
[groans]
- [boy 1 whooping]
- [boy 2 laughing]
- [laughs] Ho-ho! Yeah!
- [boy 3] Ooh!
This is your punishment for earlier.
- I'm gonna burn you.
- [gasps]
- [boys] Oh!
- Please. Please.
[boy 1] Uh-oh. That looks dangerous!
- Oh, that's close!
- [tin clatters]
- [choking]
- Huh?
- Let's go! Let's go!
- You need something?
[boy] Don't butt in.
[choking]
No one's coming to save
your little bitch ass!
[laughing boisterously]
- [boy] Scary!
- [all laughing]
[shuddering]
I don't…
I don't deserve this.
- Whoa! That's dangerous!
- Burn him!
- Burn him! [laughing]
- [Kirino] Shit! Shit, shit, shit, shit.
[grunting]
[laughing]
- [gasps]
- [raspy growling]
[screaming]
[growling]
[screeching]
[all gasping]
[dog barking in distance]
What's that?
[suspenseful music playing]
Hold on, Kuwabara.
Hold on, Kuwabara. Wait! Wait!
- [roaring]
- [screaming]
- Get him! Get him!
- [indistinct yelling]
[grunting]
- [roaring]
- [boys screaming]
[grunting]
[boys panting]
[screeching]
[panting]
[boys panting, whimpering]
Wait-- that's… that's a… Fire! Fire! Run!
[boys screaming]
Get out of here!
- Get out of here!
- The kid's gone nuts!
[screaming]
Hey! Hey! What the hell, man?!
- [screaming]
- What's going on?
- [friend 1] Wait! Kuwabara!
- [friend 2] Kuwabara!
[dramatic music playing]
[Kirino screeching]
[gasping, growling]
- [gasping, choking]
- [bones crunching]
[whooshing]
Don't be stressed over all that.
Yusuke! [gasps]
[sighs]
[somber music playing]
[exhales deeply]
[gasps]
[grunts]
[Yusuke] Hey, Botan.
[Botan] Yes?
To get resurrected…
what do I need to do?
[chuckles] You've finally decided,
have you?
I'm glad! We've got some
preparation to do, in that case.
Wait here a second.
[whooshing]
[inhales deeply]
[exhales shakily]
[Atsuko gasps]
[breathing heavily]
Huh? Huh?
[rapid footsteps approaching]
[Botan panting]
Koenma! What's the condition
of Yusuke's body?
I revived his body,
but we've got a bigger issue right now.
- [woman sobbing]
- [man yelling]
- [Botan] Huh?
- [Enma] Yusuke, can you hear me?
It's an emergency.
[tense music playing]
Wh-- What's going on?
A yokai has taken over a human.
He's on a rampage.
Your home could be in danger.
[tense music continues]
- [alarm sounding]
- [sirens wailing]
- [panting]
- [Atsuko screaming] Yusuke!
[man] Stop! Stop, you have to stop!
It's dangerous!
[Atsuko] Let go of me!
[panting]
Yusuke's alive! My son is in there!
- [grunts]
- You can't bring him back.
No, he's alive!
I saw the color come back to his face!
I could feel the heat in his chest!
- That's not possible!
- It's dangerous!
- [Atsuko] Stop!
- [man 1] You can't go!
- [Atsuko] Let go!
- [man 1] You can't go in there!
[Atsuko] Let me go! Please!
I said let me go!
- [man 1] You gotta stay back!
- [man 2] Hey! Hey!
- Idiot!
- Keiko!
[breathing heavily, yelps]
- [men clamoring]
- [gasps]
[panting]
- Leave this place!
- [Keiko grunting]
Forget about my body and run!
Hey!
[fire hissing, whooshing]
Dang. You're completely trapped.
[grunting]
[panting]
[straining]
[coughing]
[somber music playing]
[Yusuke] Hey, Keiko.
Hey, Keiko!
[Keiko coughs softly]
Hey! Keiko!
[wood creaking]
[hopeful music playing]
Oh wow.
[Yusuke] Hey, Koenma, let me save Keiko.
'Cause if she dies,
there's no point in living again.
[breathing shakily]
[grunting]
I'll do whatever you say.
[breathing heavily]
Just let her live.
Those words, don't forget them.
[magical whooshing]
[epic music playing]
[magical tinkling]
[music stops abruptly]
[tense music playing]
[grunting]
[breathing heavily]
[epic music playing]
[exhales]
[Atsuko breathing heavily]
Yusuke?! What?
Sorry, let's talk later.
Look after Keiko.
[breathing heavily]
Keiko…
Hey, Koenma, what was that about a yokai?
[Enma] That roundworm I mentioned.
It possesses people
with negative emotions and amplifies them.
So this is all that thing's fault.
- [objects shattering]
- [fire blazing]
[Enma] Yusuke, I'm giving you
your first order as Spirit Detective.
Stop that monster whatever it takes.
I think I'm going to enjoy this.
- [grunting]
- [boy] Kuwabara!
- This guy's not normal.
- [grunting]
[raspy growling]
- [boy 2] Hey, get off him!
- [growling]
You bastard!
[grunting]
[screeching]
[yelps]
- [raspy growling]
- [all grunting, panting]
- [growls]
- [groans]
- [raspy grunt]
- [gasps]
[screaming]
[grunting]
[boy grunting]
[Kirino grunts]
[boy] Let him go!
[screeching ferociously]
- [grunts]
- [screaming]
S-- Sawamura!
[Sawamura screaming]
[Kuwabara grunting]
- [screeching]
- [yelps]
[Kuwabara grunting]
[Kuwabara panting] Dammit!
- [growls]
- [grunts]
[groans]
[gasping]
[croaking]
[music intensifies]
[panting]
[shrieks, grunts]
[Kuwabara] Urameshi?
Why…
[grunts]
[Yusuke breathing heavily]
[Kirino grunting]
- [raspy breathing]
- [rod clangs]
Snap out of it now!
[grunting]
[Yusuke] What the…
- [roars]
- [Yusuke grunts]
[panting]
[Enma] Yusuke!
He's possessed by the roundworm monster.
His body is under its control.
That means what, exactly?
[Enma] If you don't get it out of him
quickly, he'll turn into a yokai!
[screeching]
[grunting]
[yells]
[growling]
[grunting]
[screeching]
[Yusuke yells]
[grunting]
How exactly do I chase it out?
[Enma] Your only hope is
to use Spirit Energy.
What the hell is that?
[Enma] Not something
I can just teach you on the spot!
- [Yusuke grunts]
- [Kirino croaking]
- [Yusuke grunting]
- [Kirino screeching]
[loud bang]
[cans clattering]
[grunts, pants]
I need to learn how to use it right now!
Okay, listen well.
First, focus all of your Spirit Energy
in one part of your body.
Next, and this is the most important part.
If we trace its origins,
the words "Spirit Energy--"
I don't care. Get to it!
Hmm? He asked me to teach him.
You used your Spirit Energy just now!
That's what you need to harness!
[music swelling]
[intense music playing]
[screeching]
[grunting]
[raspy growl]
What the hell is that?
[roaring]
[Yusuke grunts]
- [raspy growl]
- [gasps]
[grunting]
[screeching]
- [growls]
- [Yusuke grunts]
[roaring]
[grunts]
[Kirino snarling]
[screeching]
[shrieks]
Yusuke!
Calm down, Botan.
[Botan breathing heavily]
All we can do is have faith
and watch over him.
[thrilling music playing]
[grunting]
[screeching]
[Yusuke yells]
[grunts]
[growling]
[breathing heavily]
[Kirino snarling]
[grunting]
Hurry, Yusuke.
We're out of time.
- [screeching]
- [Yusuke grunting]
- [grunts]
- [Kirino snarls]
[grunting]
[Yusuke straining]
Get the hell outta him!
[grunts]
- [grunts]
- [Kirino snarls]
[both grunting]
[groaning]
[exhales deeply]
[Kirino croaking]
[screeching]
[roaring]
[Yusuke grunting]
[gas hissing]
[hissing]
[Yusuke grunting]
[roaring]
[panting]
[gas hissing]
[exploding]
[gasping]
[grunts, pants]
[grunts]
[grunting]
[gasps]
[raspy grunting]
[wheezy breathing]
[grunting]
[gasps]
[growling]
[panting]
[somber music playing]
[grunting]
- [grunting]
- [Kirino snarling]
Come on, Kirino!
Just snap out of it already!
At the wake,
you stood up to those bullies.
[breathing heavily]
But you're gonna let some insect
boss you around?
Snap the hell out of it!
[Kirino panting]
[breathing heavily]
Yusuke, help.
[dramatic music playing]
[growls]
[grunts]
[panting]
[Kirino snarling]
Kirino, I'm gonna save your ass.
[panting]
[snarling]
- [Kirino grunts]
- [breathing heavily]
[whimpering, grunting]
Get the hell…
[music intensifies]
out of there!
[squealing]
Hey, you bastard!
[yells]
[panting]
[music fades]
[classical music playing over speakers]
[sinister music playing]
[groaning]
[breathing heavily]
[grunting]
[Kuwabara] Hey, guys…
[breathing heavily]
[grunting]
Sawamura?
Hey, Sawamura!
[grunting]
Hey, Kuwabara.
Urameshi?
Check on your pals. Go on.
[pensive music playing]
[door slides open]
[Atsuko] Huh?
[Atsuko breathing heavily]
[Keiko breathing shakily]
Yusuke?
Is it really… [gasps]
Yeah.
I'm not gonna die
just 'cause you talk shit.
[breathing deeply]
[inhales sharply]
That hurts. Get off me!
[laughs]
[uplifting music playing]
Good to see you.
[inhales deeply]
Yeah, I'm back.
[laughs]
Yusuke!
Come on. Stop it!
- [Atsuko sobbing]
- Please. Serious?!
What is this?
I said I get it!
That was a close call in a lot of ways.
[Enma sighs]
If that's how our new
Spirit Detective fights, we're in trouble.
Huh?
From what I've heard,
they're after you-know-what.
[rumbling]
He's gonna have to fight those things?
That's not fair.
Yusuke won't even stand a chance.
I know that.
[sighs] But we have no choice.
We can't let it be used for evil,
no matter what.
[pulsating slowly]
- [guns firing]
- [people screaming]
[growling]
[guns firing]
[roaring]
[screaming]
[snarling]
[growling in distance]
[thunder crashing]
- [snarling]
- [guns firing]
[thrilling music playing]
[sword swishing]
[screeching]
[snarling]
[sword swishing]
[growls]
[thrilling music continues]
[snarling]
[whooshing]
[screeching]
[growling]
[croaks]
[grunts]
[thrilling music playing]
[frantic snarling]
[rumbling]
[roaring ferociously]
[pulsating slowly]
[growling]
- [sword swishes]
- [screeching]
[grunts]
[thunder crashes]
[pulsating]
[tense music playing]
[theme music playing]
[dramatic music playing]
[music ends]