[dramatic music playing]
[dramatic beat plays]
Hey.
Keiko had better be safe. Got that?
Why of course.
If you defeat the yokai
that the master is keeping,
we promise we will return the girl to you.
[dramatic music continues]
Sounds like a tournament.
I'd guess they have
a lot of money riding on it.
Say again?
[Kurama] I hear that they're getting yokai
to fight each other to the death.
[Kuwabara] What for?
It's the rich just having fun.
I'm sure that there's more.
They wanna see something bad happen.
We have to be careful.
[Kuwabara] There's no way humans
would do that.
[dramatic music continues]
[music fades]
[classical music playing]
[Sakyo] Even though
it was a last minute invitation,
there wasn't a single absentee.
Everyone must really love
to gamble, right?
Hmm. You're the one who likes
to gamble, aren't you?
- I like to pretend that I like it.
- Ahh.
[coins clinking]
[Sakyo] Heads or tails?
Why are you doing this?
[Sakyo] It's just for fun.
Huh.
Tails, then.
I won this one.
[Tarukane] Yeah? What's your point?
Let's go again.
[Tarukane] All right. Heads.
Who cares? [grunts]
[Sakyo] Yeah. It is pointless.
I'd win any bet you put in front of me.
What I'm saying is, I don't lose.
Now you're talking nonsense.
[drawer opens]
[ominous music plays]
[grunting]
Just listen.
Only four times I've gambled
with life instead of chips.
So not that often.
There were other opportunities…
but once people realize I'm serious,
they always pull out.
[music continues]
[whirring]
[Sakyo] How about it?
Like an opening game before the big event.
[pensive music playing]
The ones who took the bet,
they were people
with rotten brains like mine.
[sighs] Gambling's the only thing
I care for.
Life's too slow.
I can't be fulfilled…
[gun cocks]
…in life.
- [gun clicking]
- [gasps]
[exhales sharply]
[ominous music continues]
I'll win the next game, too.
So that I can fulfill my dream
and destroy this boredom at last.
[music fades]
Excuse me, Koenma.
Genkai's death, you…
you haven't told him yet?
[sighing]
Not yet.
It's too much.
He needs to stay focused
on the task at hand.
[dramatic music playing]
[low growl]
[exhaling]
[gasping]
[gasps]
Yusuke.
[music continues]
- [theme music playing]
- [Enma] Training under Genkai,
Kuwabara was able
to master the Spirit Sword.
Holy shit, I did it!
[Enma] Yusuke inherited the power
of the Spirit Wave Orb.
[Genkai] The world needs you
now more than ever.
[Enma] But during that time,
Keiko was kidnapped by Elder Toguro.
After learning that Yukina,
Hiei's estranged younger sister,
was also taken,
Yusuke and his company head
to Kubikukuri Island to rescue them.
While all this was going on…
[Genkai] Looks like the years
have been kind to you.
[Enma] Genkai was assassinated
by Younger Toguro,
who once trained under her.
[music ends]
[footsteps approaching]
[suspenseful music playing]
This is as far as I go with you.
- [Kuwabara] Huh?
- I work alone.
[whizzing]
[trees rustling]
Oh, so he thinks he can
do this all on his own!
Hiei's worried too, all right?
So take it easy.
[grunting]
[music continues]
[music stops]
[ominous music playing]
Do you use hair treatment?
[music intensifies]
You should take good care of it.
Humans are so fragile, after all.
- You bastard!
- I'll handle this.
You go on ahead.
All I want is your beautiful soul.
I'll be fine.
See you soon.
Well, good luck.
Kurama, don't you dare die!
I didn't know Youko Kurama
pretended to have friends.
That's a bad joke.
You mean…
You know about me?
[man] Of course I know.
I know the ruthless,
stone-cold yokai you used to be.
[intense music playing]
[wind whistling]
[suspenseful music playing]
[footsteps thudding]
[music intensifies]
You're in my way. Go on.
[fast-paced dramatic music playing]
If you won't move, then I'll make you.
[grunting]
[yells]
[exhales]
[Tarukane] Ten billion yen!
I'll bet ten on Bui!
[laughing] Tarukane,
you're really going all in, huh?
Of course! I want to watch Hiei pay
for trying to take my life.
One billion on Bui and Karasu.
[man] In that case, I'll bet, uh,
two billion on Karasu and Bui.
[both grunting]
[whipping]
[grunting]
[grunts]
[dramatic music playing]
[grunting]
[swishing]
[Karasu grunting]
[Kurama grunting]
[gasps]
[Karasu] How long are you going to fight
in your present form?
[sighing]
[grunting, panting]
[roaring]
[dramatic music playing]
[grunting]
[grunts, yells]
- [grunts]
- [swishing]
[Karasu grunting]
[Kurama grunting]
[music continues]
[both panting]
- Let's go on our own.
- Okay.
[grunts, pants]
So, that creature that took me,
you're saying it was a yokai, for real?
Yes.
[sighing]
This is just too crazy.
Hey, so
could you let me take a look at your hand?
Huh?
Your injury.
Oh. You mean this?
[mystical tone]
[soft piano music playing]
You should know
I'm a yokai too.
[dramatic music playing]
[both grunting]
[Karasu grunts]
[Kurama grunts]
[grunting continues]
[grunting]
[gasping]
[rumbling]
[music intensifies]
[whizzing]
[grunting]
[Karasu breathes deeply]
Oh, you're trying to be clever.
[groaning]
Do you really think you can win
while taking the form of a human?
[music continues]
[Karasu breathing shakily]
[breathing deeply]
[Kurama] Indeed, the human body,
it is a little heavy for the task at hand.
[dramatic music playing]
[Japanese combat music playing]
[Karasu grunts]
[Kurama] I told myself I would never
go back to this form again.
[music intensifies]
[hissing]
[clanging]
[Bui yells]
[grunting]
[groaning]
[breathes deeply]
[Bui snarls]
[ethereal music playing]
The Ojigi Plants are quick to anger.
Your movements will draw their attention.
I suggest you don't move,
if you want to stay alive.
- [action music playing]
- [grunting]
- [Hiei grunts]
- [weapon clangs]
- [Bui grunts]
- [sword clangs]
[sword swishes]
[Bui snarls]
[both grunting]
[groaning]
[grunting]
[groans]
[Hiei panting]
[Bui] Oh, I see.
In order to defeat you
I shall have to remove my armor.
[thuds]
[armor thudding]
[dramatic music playing]
[growling]
[rumbling]
[Keiko moaning]
Hey, what's wrong?
Hey!
[moaning and whimpering]
[man] What's wrong?
Come on, get up. What's wrong?
[grunting]
[both grunting]
Let-- No!
[panting]
I guess Yusuke's wrestling lessons
came in handy after all.
[tense music playing]
[exhales]
- [computer beeps]
- [gate unlocks]
Let's go!
[breathing shakily]
- I'll stay. You run away now.
- You can't stay.
There was someone before
who was killed trying to help me.
If that happened to you, I…
Come on, don't give up.
You owe it to that person
to get out of here.
I feel like
I owe you for healing my wound earlier.
Look, I will drag you out
by the neck if I have to.
[soft piano music playing]
Oh, and my name is Keiko.
What's yours?
It's Yukina.
- [dramatic music playing]
- [Ojigi plant hissing]
[grunting]
- [hissing]
- [Karasu grunts]
[grunts, yells]
[grunting]
[groaning]
[screaming]
[grunting continues]
[ethereal music playing]
[grunting]
[Kurama breathing heavily]
[straining]
[gasping]
[yells]
[grunts]
[Kurama grunts]
- [gasping]
- [Karasu panting]
This is fun, Kurama.
My bloodlust grows stronger.
[Kurama gasping]
[gasping]
[Karasu] Oh, I see.
Well, I guess you're out of energy, right?
[Kurama grunting]
- [whooshes]
- [Kurama grunts]
[gasping]
- [sword clangs]
- [grunts]
[both grunting]
[panting]
[dramatic music playing]
[whooshing, rumbling]
- [grunts]
- [sword clangs]
[both grunting]
Kill him now! Just do it!
- Go, go, go, go, go!
- Agh!
Come on, concentrate, concentrate.
- [Tarukane] Finish him!
- [man] What are you doing?
Defense, defense!
That's it, yes, yes, yes!
- [Tarukane] Kill him! Keep attacking!
- [man] Yes, focus!
- Concentrate!
- [Tarukane] Don't back down now!
- [man 1] Good, good. Yes! Focus, focus!
- [Tarukane] Go! Kill! Kill!
[man] Turn around, turn around! Wow, wow.
- Oh, good, good, good. Yes!
- [Tarukane] That's it!
[tense music playing]
[both gasp]
[footsteps approaching]
[exhales]
Let's go.
[exhales sharply]
[tense music continues]
- [metallic clang]
- [both gasp]
[breathing shakily]
[breathes deeply]
[tense music continues]
[rapid footsteps approaching]
[both gasp]
[tense music continues]
[music intensifies]
- [music stops abruptly]
- [footsteps approaching]
- [Keiko grunts]
- [Kuwabara groans]
[groaning]
That hurts!
- Oh, Kuwabara?!
- [Kuwabara grunts]
[groaning]
Oh, Yukimura. You escaped?
Oh, yeah. Are you in a lot of pain?
[Kuwabara groaning]
You're the first person to hit me
since I got here, but it's…
not too bad.
[soft music playing]
Yu-- Yukimura.
Wh-- Who's that woman standing beside you?
Right there?
Oh! [chuckles]
Oh, right. This is Yukina.
- [Kuwabara gasps]
- [chuckles]
Are you serious? You're really her?!
Huh? Oh. Yes.
Well, anyway, Kuwabara,
are you here to rescue us?
Yes.
I, Kazuma Kuwabara,
in order to aid in your escape,
have come hither, to this accursed place.
Uh… Thank you very much.
[Kuwabara sighs]
[electro music playing]
[Enma] Yusuke.
I want to ask you something.
What is it?
[Enma] Have you mastered using the
Spirit Wave Orb you received from Genkai?
No big deal.
I'm not gonna let her down.
Yusuke…
Actually, Genkai was…
[exhales] What?
Genkai also had this to say.
[music continues]
[Enma] "Don't you dare lose, Yusuke."
That's it.
Right.
That's obvious.
[panting]
[music continues]
[weapons clanging]
[grunting]
[Hiei grunts]
[groaning]
[clattering]
[Bui] Hmm.
Mmm.
Hmm.
[rumbling]
- [Bui gasps]
- [Hiei grunts]
[rumbling]
[breathing heavily]
[grunts]
[panting]
I wanted this to remain hidden
until the very end.
[grunts]
[intriguing music playing]
But there's no backing out now
since I've forgotten
how to put it back on.
[intense music playing]
[growling]
[roaring]
[grunting]
- [rumbling]
- [yells]
[growls]
[grunting]
[straining]
[grunts]
[shrieking]
[whooshing]
[screams]
[grunts]
[dramatic flourish playing]
[breathing shakily]
[Bui breathing feebly]
Finish it.
[grunting feebly]
My life serves no purpose.
Toguro beat me too.
[exhales]
Please, just kill me.
If you want to die, go ahead.
I don't like being told what to do.
[Bui groans]
- [whooshing]
- [Kurama grunts]
[yells]
[grunting]
[panting]
[both grunting]
[yells, grunts]
[groaning]
[sighs]
You should stop now if you want to live.
[Kurama gasping]
This supernatural energy,
it's the same wherever I am, right?
Precisely. You're learning.
[rumbling, whooshing]
[grunts]
[panting]
It'd be easy to blow you to smithereens,
but I choose not to.
[gasping]
[energy rumbling, whooshing]
[Kurama yelps]
[coughs]
[groaning]
I'll leave that beautiful head
undamaged as it is.
[breathes deeply]
[ominous music playing]
[Kurama laughing]
Did I knock your brain loose?
[Kurama] Do you know
the Seed of the Death Plant?
Gardening? Sounds boring.
[Kurama] It's a parasitic plant that takes
root in the bodies of living creatures.
When I say a certain word, it'll…
begin to grow explosively…
and it will tear you apart.
[dramatic flourish playing]
[intense music playing]
[grunts]
[music continues]
[exhales deeply]
Those roots are inside you right now.
They've grown everywhere.
[gasps]
[whooshing]
I'm glad that you're heartless.
[thumping]
[grunts]
Because I too can kill without hesitation.
[gasping]
[groaning]
[breathing shakily]
Die!
[thumping, squirting]
[Kurama panting]
[grunts]
[panting]
Huh! Well, this is quite a surprise!
[scoffs] They defeated
the invincible Bui and Karasu!
[man 1] Those two really are strong.
[man 2] Even though I lost some money,
this has still been pretty amusing.
[chuckles] I was starting to get bored.
Well, gentlemen,
your bets will now be collected.
Still, I'm glad you all enjoyed it.
So, Tarukane,
even though you lost ten billion
you must've enjoyed it too, right?
You don't look so well, eh? Tarukane.
[laughing]
[man 3] This sort of thing
happens a lot in gambling.
My friend, don't be a sore loser
and say you're quitting.
[laughs]
The game is just getting started.
- [men laughing]
- [man 3] That's the spirit.
As Tarukane just said,
we do have our main event to get to.
[ominous music playing]
Huh?
[sighs]
[breathing heavily]
[gasps]
[door buzzing]
Go try that one.
- [computer beeps]
- [alarm sounding]
[whirring]
Bingo. That's the one. [chuckles]
Huh?
[low growl]
We need to go.
Let's go!
- [roaring]
- [all panting]
- [growling]
- [pipes clattering]
- [glass shattering]
- [all panting]
- [roaring]
- [Kuwabara whimpering]
[grunting]
- Go! What the hell is that!?
- [roaring]
[roaring ferociously]
[gasps]
Kuwabara!
You go ahead!
[Yukina yelps]
Yukina!
[gasps]
[growling]
Hey, Yukimura!
[Keiko grunts]
[groans]
[Kuwabara] Yukina, are you all right?
- [growling]
- [gasps]
Yukimura, out of the way!
- [roaring]
- [Keiko gasps]
- [Yukina grunts]
- [Kuwabara grunts]
[growling]
[roars]
- [grunts]
- Kuwabara!
- [Yukina gasps]
- [roars]
[snarling]
- [Yukina gasps]
- [loud clanging]
Yeah, Yukimura! Nice!
Hey, monster! Over here!
Over here! Hey!
Over here, yo! Hey! Look this way!
- Your turn!
- [grunts]
- [Kuwabara grunts]
- [Yukina and Keiko panting]
- [Kuwabara grunting]
- [growling]
Kuwabara! Run!
No!
[screaming]
The shutters.
[grunting]
Whoa! Whoa!
[gasps]
- Out of the way! [grunts]
- [glass shatters]
[alarm sounding]
[roaring]
Kuwabara, hurry!
Kuwabara, run!
[panting]
[screaming]
- [grunting]
- [snarling]
[roaring]
[Kuwabara screaming]
[growling]
- [Yukina yelps]
- [loud thud]
- Go now!
- [Keiko panting]
[Kurama grunting]
[breathes deeply]
Looks like you had a tough fight.
I'm guessing your right hand's
out of commission for a while.
[clicks tongue]
No, I can keep going.
[breathing heavily]
[all panting]
[Yukina] Kuwabara! Please be careful!
[panting]
He kidnapped me!
That's the guy who did it!
Son of a bitch! I'll tear you in half!
This isn't what I wanted.
You're doing the unexpected.
- Just shut it!
- Oh…
[grunting]
[Younger Toguro gasping]
[laughing]
[gasps]
[grunts]
[laughs]
[grunting]
[Kuwabara gasps]
[Younger Toguro grunting]
Someone is going to die again
because of you.
[laughs maniacally]
[gasps]
[tense music playing]
[Sakyo over speaker]
Well done for making it here, Urameshi.
I'm sorry I was so rough with your friend.
I apologize.
You bastard!
Where is Keiko?!
[Sakyo] I'll return Keiko
if you defeat him.
Toguro,
sorry for the wait.
[footsteps approaching]
[ominous music playing]
We'll start with a warm-up, shall we?
[inhales deeply]
- [growls]
- [whooshing]
[exhales]
[grunts]
That Spirit Wave Orb.
I wanna see the power she gave you.
How'd you know that?
For this round, if you get it right,
I'll triple your bet.
Are you sure?! Ten billion on Toguro!
Then, I'll stake 12 on Toguro!
I'll bet…
twenty on Toguro!
Excuse me.
It's ready.
The wormhole is now open, sir.
[laughs]
[intense music playing]
[laughing hysterically]
[crackling]
[Sakyo continues laughing hysterically]
[theme music playing]
[dramatic music playing]
[music ends]