[muffled noise]
[muffled scream]
[scream getting louder]
[ethereal music playing]
[screaming]
[gasping]
[man] Help!
Help!
[screaming]
[theme music playing]
[Enma] Yusuke and the others arrived
at Kubikukuri Island
to rescue Keiko and Yukina.
Unaware of Genkai's death,
Yusuke squared off against Younger Toguro.
That Spirit Wave Orb.
I want to see the power she gave you.
How do you know that?
[Enma] Meanwhile,
roundworm monsters begin to pour
out of the opening in the sinkhole.
[laughing]
[Enma] Sakyo wants to connect
the Demon World and the Human World.
In the end,
is there any hope…
- [Sakyo laughing hysterically]
- …of stopping him?
[sighs]
[grunts gently]
Asshole.
[action music playing]
- [grunts]
- [Yusuke yells, grunts]
[grunts]
[Younger Toguro laughs]
- [gasps]
- [Younger Toguro grunts]
[both grunt]
[groans]
[Younger Toguro] Mmm.
I'll go harder from now on.
[panting]
[grunts]
[grunting]
- [yells]
- [rumbling]
[gasps]
[exhales]
[rumbling]
- [loud thud]
- [all gasp]
[electricity crackling]
[men] No! No, no, no, no, no.
[screams]
[gasps]
I thought you said we were safe!
Well,
who can say?
[men clamoring]
Hey, get outta the way! Go, go! Move!
- [grunting]
- [weapons clanging]
[grunting]
- [Elder Toguro] Ahh!
- [grunts]
- [gasps]
- [Elder Toguro yells]
- [yells]
- [grunts]
[groaning]
[panting]
[Elder Toguro sighs, laughs]
Prepare to get sliced and diced.
- [grunts]
- [clanking]
[Keiko panting]
[Kuwabara] Yukimura!
[panting]
[Elder Toguro] Aah.
[ominous music playing]
How about that? Nice try.
[grunting]
[inhales deeply]
You must really want to die first.
[laughing maniacally]
[grunting]
[huffing]
[grunting angrily]
[sword buzzing]
[yelling]
[grunting]
[gasps, laughs]
[yelling]
[laughing maniacally]
- [screaming]
- [Elder Toguro yells]
[screams]
[grunts]
[panting]
[sword buzzing]
It's finally here! My Spirit Sword!
Master!
Why didn't you use that earlier
if you had it all along?!
Yeah? So what? I won, didn't I?
[panting]
- Kuwabara…
- [Kuwabara] Huh?
- Kuwabara!
- [exhales sharply]
[Kuwabara gasps]
- [Keiko gasps]
- [Kuwabara grunts]
[grunts]
- [panting]
- [Elder Toguro grunting]
Someone as naive as you…
[grunting]
…is perfect for me to toy around with.
[ominous music playing]
[rustling]
[dramatic music playing]
[Botan breathing heavily]
[gasps] Come quickly!
[Enma panting]
[whooshing]
[energy humming]
[dramatic music playing]
[exploding]
[grunting]
- [Botan sighs]
- [Enma panting]
This thing won't hold for long.
What do you mean?
The hole is expanding too quickly.
There's clearly an artificial force.
[dramatic music continues]
[Yusuke grunts]
[energy buzzing]
[grunts]
[yells]
[grunting]
[panting]
[metal clanging]
[both grunting]
[grunts]
Mmm.
That was close. Not bad, Yusuke.
[pants, grunts]
[grunts]
[groans]
You finally decided to reveal yourself.
You bastard.
Do you have any idea what you are doing?
By widening that hole,
yokai are going to come swarming through.
That's correct.
Don't do this.
Nobody in the city will be safe.
Tell me what you're trying to achieve.
I want to see a larger world.
The way it was
before you separated
the Human World from the Demon World.
The world as it should be.
We need that small hole
to grow even larger
to join the Human
and Demon Worlds together.
Don't you want to remove these borders,
and strive for a better world?
[Enma breathing heavily]
I'm not gonna let you do that!
Is that right?
So this barrier of yours,
I wonder how long it will last.
[tense music playing]
[Sakyo] The fact that you're
showing your face here
means that the barrier
won't hold for much longer, right?
[tense music continues]
[exhales smoke]
What'll it be?
How would you feel
about raising the stakes a little?
[grunting]
[groaning]
[gasps]
[grunts]
[loud clang]
[electricity crackling]
Hiei!
Sorry.
We were delayed.
Kurama…
Thank you.
[Hiei] Listen, Yusuke.
I'm not doing this to help you, all right?
[laughs]
Let's do it.
Shall we play?
Play what?
If your guys win, I'll stop the machine.
On the other hand, if Toguro wins,
you'll take down that barrier.
[Enma scoffs]
Even if we win,
you could always build
another machine just like this.
All right.
Why don't I bet my life on it?
I've devoted my whole life to this dream.
So, I don't mind
if it costs me my life.
Those words,
don't forget them.
[pensive music playing]
[Sakyo over speakers] Toguro.
Apologies, but please fight all of them.
Does this mean the plan's changed?
Yes. That's right.
Aye-aye, sir.
[Enma] Sorry, Yusuke.
I'm leaving the fate of the world
in your hands.
Who cares about saving the world?
I came here to take this guy out
and save Keiko.
Let's go.
[inhales deeply, grunts]
[action music playing]
[grunting]
[sword swishes]
[whipping]
[grunting]
[grunting, panting]
- [grunting]
- [sword swishing]
[music stops]
[dramatic music playing]
[grunting]
- [Yusuke yelling]
- [Younger Toguro grunts]
[music stops]
[inhales sharply]
[panting]
How nice.
[grunts angrily]
[all grunt]
[exhales]
[pants, grunts]
[grunting]
[groans]
[grunts]
[groaning]
[gasping]
[grunting]
[thrilling music playing]
- [all panting]
- [Elder Toguro laughing]
[Tarukane panting]
Wha-- What the hell is going on?
[whimpering]
Wha---
Where has she gone?!
[low growl]
Huh?
- [growls]
- [Tarukane yelps]
[whimpering]
- [roars]
- [Tarukane screams]
[grunting]
[breathing shakily]
[thrilling music playing]
[grunting]
[straining]
[whipping]
[Yusuke grunting]
[Younger Toguro] Mmm.
[grunting]
Mmm.
[whooshing]
[grunting]
Hmm.
[whooshing]
Mmm.
[grunting]
[yells]
[rumbling]
[panting]
[electricity crackling]
[groaning]
[sighs]
[grunting]
[footsteps rumbling]
[grunts, pants]
[grunts]
[footsteps rumbling]
[Younger Toguro sighs]
[breathing shakily]
[exhales]
[footsteps thudding]
Hmm.
Was that really the best you could do?
I was a fool for expecting anything else.
[breathes deeply]
It would be pointless
to fight you at full strength.
[ominous music playing]
[alarm sounding]
[all panting]
[Kuwabara] Shit, we won't make it.
[panting]
Shit.
[shutter whirring]
[all gasp]
[breathing heavily]
[both breathing heavily]
- [punch landing]
- [Yusuke grunts]
[groaning]
Yusuke!
No! Stay!
- [Kuwabara gasps]
- [Elder Toguro exhales]
You bastard!
[Elder Toguro chuckles]
[laughs]
Hey, hey, hey!
You've already handled things here?
[laughing]
[humming]
[gasps] Those poor things.
[laughs]
And over here, too? [laughs]
I knew my brother wouldn't
let us down. [laughs]
It looks like Genkai
really did die in vain after all!
- [laughs hysterically]
- [breathing heavily]
Master?
What a minute. What did you just say?
Huh?
Oh no.
[laughing] You really didn't know?
[laughs]
[inhales deeply]
In that case, let me teach you.
Watch and learn.
Here's what you need to know.
Stop it.
Our story begins
with a young woman and a young man.
They were friends.
The two of them wanted to become
martial arts masters together.
However,
as the years passed,
the woman, she grew old and ugly.
While the man, for the sake of training,
became a yokai
with the help of the Demon World,
all in order to preserve his youth.
Toguro
was human once?
[gasps]
[rumbling]
[Elder Toguro] The woman,
after giving away her power to a student,
made the foolish decision
to challenge him to a fight.
So they fought,
though she was no match for him.
Aah.
That's how my little brother
killed Genkai…
[grunts]
…and sent her up to heaven.
What a happy ending. [chuckles]
[laughing]
[breathing heavily]
[continues laughing]
[grunts]
[choking]
You're in my way, brother.
[grunting, panting]
Hey, hey, hey.
[inhales deeply] Let go!
What do you think you're doing?
You pawned your soul off too, didn't you?
That's irrelevant.
[Elder Toguro screaming]
[rumbling]
Hmm.
I don't remember selling my honor.
[Kuwabara breathing heavily]
[grunting]
[yelling]
[screaming]
You son of a bitch!
[buzzing]
[breathing heavily]
Why the hell…
did you kill our master, huh?!
[Spirit Sword buzzing]
[grunting]
[gasping]
[grunts, gasps]
[grunting]
After entrusting her secret to a student,
she was worthless.
And yet,
it was a mistake giving it to him.
She was desperate.
Genkai knew she had
to get you out of there.
[Kuwabara groaning]
[breathing shakily]
[Genkai] The world needs you,
now more than ever.
[pensive music playing]
[inaudible]
Your training is hereby complete.
You may leave this mountain.
Get stronger, Yusuke.
Because there are people depending on you.
[motivational music playing]
[grunting]
[grunts, exhales]
[choking]
[motivational music continues]
[grunting]
[exhales]
[choking]
[grunts]
[yelling]
[dramatic music playing]
[grunts]
[grunting]
[screaming]
- [rumbling]
- [grunts]
[panting]
[gasps]
[both gasp]
[grunting]
So cool.
So that's the Spirit Wave Orb.
This means you can win, Yusuke!
Unfortunately,
that's not possible anymore.
What?
[rocks falling]
[faint rumbling]
- [rumbling intensifies]
- [deep exhale]
[gasps]
[loud rumbling]
[Yusuke gasps]
[Kuwabara gasps]
[both gasp]
[rumbling continues]
[breathing shakily]
[gasps]
[loud rumbling, crashing]
[breathing heavily]
[rumbling]
[gasps]
[breathing heavily]
[loud whoosh]
[eerie deep exhale]
[breathing heavily]
[grunting]
- [footsteps thudding]
- [eerie breathing]
I have to take back what I said earlier.
[panting]
[Younger Toguro]
You are the first person I can call
a rival.
[chandelier tinkling]
You see, originally,
this battle was planned
with Yusuke as the winner.
Huh?
To squeeze even more money
out of the rich.
It was fixed?
Yes.
However, that's no longer necessary.
With this sudden change of plans,
we can now begin to really have fun.
[Enma breathing nervously]
[Younger Toguro] Hmm.
[Yusuke panting]
[rumbling]
[Kuwabara grunts]
[objects clattering]
[Kuwabara groaning]
[both breathing shakily]
[breathing heavily]
[Younger Toguro] This is pure strength.
The power I wield in just the snap
of a finger can be a weapon.
[whizzing]
[grunting]
[grunts]
[yelling]
[gasps]
[choking]
[gasping]
[Younger Toguro] Based on my experience
as a former human,
you're missing something important.
[gasping]
A sense of urgency.
[grunts]
[choking]
[Younger Toguro] Or could it be…
you believe you're going
to be spared from death?
- [grunting]
- Hmm.
It's possible
I may have made a very dangerous bet.
[tense music playing]
[muffled explosions]
[sighs]
[Botan] Koenma!
Better come look!
I found out what caused
Toguro's reincarnation as a yokai!
Fifty years ago,
Toguro's very own students
were killed by a yokai named Kairen.
This yokai appeared
in order to fight Toguro,
and after winning…
those students were
devoured.
They were eaten!
[Younger Toguro exhales]
Your power lies dormant.
What will it take to unlock it?
How about pain?
- Fear of death?
- [gasping]
No matter the cost, it will be mine.
I'll give up my honor if I have to.
[foreboding music playing]
[both gasp]
[grunting feebly]
[rumbling]
[both panting]
- [Younger Toguro] How about this?
- [Yusuke grunts]
The next one will hit.
[breathing heavily]
[grunting]
Rage, as expected.
[grunts angrily]
[grunts]
[groans]
That's good, but it's not enough.
[intriguing music playing]
Anger alone won't suffice.
- [exhales deeply]
- [both gasp]
[grunting feebly]
Hmm.
Was I not clear?
No, please.
The next will hit.
[breathing shakily]
[screaming] No! Please! Stop!
Stop it!
- [Hiei grunts]
- [Yukina and Keiko gasp]
[Hiei grunts]
[grunting]
[both panting]
[Younger Toguro] You're in the way.
[breathing heavily]
[footsteps thudding]
[Kuwabara grunting]
[Kurama grunts]
[both whimpering]
[grunting]
[both grunting]
[grunts]
[groaning]
Hiei!
[continues groaning]
Kurama!
[grunts]
I still… owe you one.
[grunts, groans]
- [both whimpering]
- [Kurama grunting]
[gasping]
[weakly] Kurama!
[exhales deeply]
[both whimpering]
- [Younger Toguro exhales]
- [Kuwabara panting]
I won't let you.
[panting]
You'll be my next victim, then.
Urameshi needs a little encouragement.
[yelling]
- [Younger Toguro exhales]
- [panting]
Must be tough to watch, Urameshi.
Because you are…
powerless.
[punch landing]
[breathes nervously]
[grunting feebly]
Urameshi, you're supposed
to be stronger than this.
[squelches]
[somber music playing]
[music intensifies]
[breathing feebly]
[straining]
[breathes deeply]
[grunting]
[Yusuke grunting]
[music fades]
[Yusuke breathing heavily]
Unforgivable.
I can't forgive myself most of all.
[whooshing]
His Spirit Energy
is almost a match for Toguro's power.
[gasps] Yes, but can he still fight
with his Energy in such disarray?
I don't know.
Right now, underpinning Yusuke's
Spirit Energy is tremendous sadness.
It's incredibly strong,
but unreliable.
[Botan breathing deeply]
[soft music playing]
I'm here to protect all of my friends.
My promise to Master Genkai.
Your friends are no more than an obstacle.
Let them go.
You and I are quite alike.
Throw everything else away
and grow stronger.
I'm not like you, Toguro.
I can't go it alone.
I gave Master Genkai my word.
[Younger Toguro] How naive.
[grunts]
How very naive.
You're nothing more than Genkai's student.
What will it take for you to understand?
Do I have to kill all of your friends?
[somber music playing]
I finally understand the price you paid
for your strength.
Master Genkai told us…
"The power you have is not real strength."
[Spirit Gun whooshing]
[Yusuke] I won't let you kill anyone else.
That's why I'm stopping this now.
That's better.
All of this power's going in one shot.
This Spirit Gun attack!
[whooshing]
[rattling]
[bottles shattering]
[rumbling]
This will decide it!
Toguro…
Do it! Yusuke!
[epic music playing]
[rumbling]
[grunting]
Yusuke…
[yelling]
Spirit Gun!
[grunts]
[rumbling]
[straining]
[grunts]
[grunting]
- [panting]
- [Younger Toguro grunting]
[continues grunting]
[grunting]
[screaming]
[gasps]
- [Younger Toguro groans]
- [Yusuke gasps]
[grunts]
[Keiko panting]
Yusuke!
- [grunting, panting]
- [Yusuke grunting feebly]
[Keiko breathing heavily]
[breathing shakily]
[exhaling]
[Younger Toguro breathing wheezily]
[gasping]
I… I give you thanks, Urameshi.
[breathing feebly]
[rumbling softly]
[exhales]
Until now, I've never had to use… [grunts]
…all this power.
[grunting]
[gasping]
This is your power I got a taste of, huh?
Not bad, Yusuke.
He…
He won.
[breathing heavily]
[rustling]
[gasping]
[Kuwabara grunting feebly]
[coughing]
[breathing heavily]
[Yukina straining]
[Kuwabara grunting]
[grunting feebly]
[Yukina breathing heavily]
[Kuwabara groaning]
Y-Yukina!
- [groaning]
- [Yukina gasps]
I'm glad… you're okay.
[breathing deeply]
I caused all this.
I'm so sorry!
[breathes deeply]
It's me who should say sorry.
Humans did these horrible things to you.
Still…
even we humans
have some good in us.
[breathing shakily]
Don't end up hating all of us.
[chuckles]
Actually…
I think that I like you guys.
[gentle music playing]
Huh?
[laughs]
- Ow! Ow!
- [Yukina] Are you okay?
- Where does it hurt?
- [Kuwabara panting, groaning]
- [Yukina] Does it still hurt?
- [Kuwabara] Ow, ow!
- [groaning]
- Sorry.
Huh? Do you need help?
- Don't move. Don't move.
- [Kuwabara groaning]
[footsteps approaching]
[grunts]
[pulsating]
[Hiei] I don't need this anymore.
Take it.
[gentle music continues]
[inhales deeply]
[sighs]
[music fades]
[rumbling]
[powering down]
[rustling]
[whooshes]
Looks like I lost this bet.
The reason was
a failure to grasp Toguro's true nature.
I suppose that's it.
[sighs]
[whooshes]
A tunnel bridging worlds,
bringing hell to all humanity…
Wish I could've seen it.
[classical music playing]
[music reaches crescendo]
[gun fires]
[seagulls cawing]
[Yukina] Uh…
Uh… Well, I have a…
a long-lost brother I'm looking for.
Although we've never seen each other.
[high-pitched ring]
[Yukina] This…
Does this mean that--
[Hiei] It's not me.
You understand?
I understand.
Can I ask who you are?
A comrade.
To all of those guys.
[sloshing]
It is possible that this is
what Toguro wanted all along.
To face someone truly powerful.
To finally experience defeat.
Regardless of his motives,
for him to voluntarily choose
the worst hell of them all.
Why's that?
I guess he wants to punish himself.
Huh?
[Enma] He said he threw his friends away,
but in reality, they were stolen from him.
The guilt from not being able to
protect them has haunted him ever since.
The road that he walked
was not one of redemption but of torture.
He said he wanted to get stronger,
but he was lying to himself.
[sighs]
What a very complicated man he was.
[pensive music playing]
[Younger Toguro] I'm surprised you knew
that I'd choose this path.
Well, I had a hunch.
Are you really going?
Haven't you already atoned enough?
This is a waste of time.
Even after getting revenge,
you still blame yourself.
Why isn't it enough?
[Younger Toguro] You're wrong.
After that, I was satisfied.
I could focus on growing my strength,
and in fact, I'm grateful
for what happened to me.
- You lie!
- [Younger Toguro] Genkai.
Would you leave me alone?
[sentimental music playing]
Koenma needs to understand…
Urameshi's power
has only begun to reveal itself.
If he messes up now…
he'll end up like me.
Even at the very end,
you're worried about the one who beat you?
You remain a fool, no matter what.
[music intensifies]
Death won't heal you, Toguro.
It doesn't have to, Genkai.
[music continues]
[music fades]
[Keiko sighs]
[Yusuke] I'm sorry, Keiko,
for getting you mixed up in all this.
[Keiko] Don't be.
I knew you'd be coming to save me.
Anyway, it wasn't all bad.
I made a friend.
Hey, thanks for saving me.
- I want you to know I wasn't scared.
- [Keiko] Isn't it amazing?
- A yokai for a friend.
- [Yukina] You were scared.
- I mean, it was a close one.
- [Yusuke] You're right.
[Kuwabara] Definitely.
You know,
I think you'll really like the city.
You did too, right?
You also made some friends.
- You'll have to show me around.
- I will.
I'll show you around for sure!
[Hiei] You should stop talking.
She's too good for you.
Hey… Come here!
What did you say, you little shit?!
- Calm down. Just ignore him.
- You stay out of this.
[Kuwabara] Get back here, Hiei!
[upbeat music playing]
[chuckles]
Yusuke, thank you.
For protecting us.
Master!
I kept my promise, didn't I?!
[chuckles]
[upbeat music playing]
♪ Face to face with a riot ♪
♪ We’re standing tall ♪
♪ We’re fighting strong ♪
♪ Rising up, feel like giants ♪
♪ We’re standing tall ♪
♪ We’re fighting strong ♪
♪ We will keep our cool
We are never rattled ♪
♪ Head strong, on target
No doubt about it ♪
♪ One time, two time
Never down for the count ♪
♪ Standing back up, each and every round ♪
♪ Show you what we got
We ain’t going away ♪
♪ You can take a shot ♪
- ♪ But we’ll be standing tall ♪
- ♪ Standing tall ♪
- ♪ Fighting strong ♪
♪ Ready for the battle
We’re here to stay ♪
♪ You can take a shot ♪
- ♪ But we’ll be standing tall ♪
- ♪ Standing tall ♪
- ♪ Fighting strong ♪
♪ If sky is the limit
We’re gonna hit it, keep on going ♪
♪ We’ll always be standing tall ♪
♪ We’ll always be fighting strong ♪
♪ Show you what we got
We ain’t going away ♪
♪ You can take a shot ♪
- ♪ But we’ll be standing tall ♪
- ♪ Standing tall ♪
- ♪ Fighting strong ♪
♪ Ready for the battle
We’re here to stay ♪
♪ You can take a shot ♪
- ♪ But we’ll be standing tall ♪
- ♪ Standing tall ♪
- ♪ Fighting strong ♪
♪ Show you what we got
We ain’t going away ♪
♪ Ready for the battle
We’re here to stay ♪
♪ We’re standing tall ♪
♪ We’re fighting strong ♪
[song ends]
[seagulls cawing]
[grunts] Just go!
Go!
[sighs]
[theme music playing]
[dramatic music playing]
[music ends]