[children playing, screaming]
[girl] One, two, three, four.
[pensive music playing]
- [children yelling]
- [pulsating]
Hello, mister. What's that thing?
[man] Oh, this?
It's something very special.
[pulsating]
[wind whooshing]
- [children shouting]
- [girl 2] What? No!
[man 2] Oh! Naoya, what's wrong? Hey!
[wind gusting]
[mystical tone]
[pulsating]
See?
It's special, isn't it?
[Enma] Yusuke Urameshi became
a Spirit Detective
so that he could come back to life.
What the hell is that?
[Koenma] He has been tasked
with catching yokai
who do evil in the Human World.
I need to learn how to use it!
[Enma] But he hasn't mastered
using his Spirit Energy.
Three dangerous objects that were being
monitored by the Spirit World
were stolen by three yokai thieves.
The question is,
can Yusuke get these objects back?
[theme music playing]
[whooshing]
[panting]
[straining]
[Botan grunting]
[grunting]
[sighs]
- What's the problem?
- [exhales]
Come on! This is important. Huh?
[rumbling]
Goki, Kurama, Hiei.
What these yokai took were all
dangerous objects with huge powers.
If we don't get them back quickly,
the Human World will be in trouble!
Yeah, big trouble.
We believed you were ready
to take on the thieves,
but not those three yokai.
- They're really strong!
- [Enma] Exactly.
Which is why I'm teaching you
how to shoot the Spirit Gun. Come on.
I didn't think you'd
be this slow to get it.
Try and concentrate!
If only you were a bit smarter, you'd--
Will you shut it!
[echoing]
- I can't concentrate because of you two!
- Huh?
And being dumb has nothing to do with it.
[Enma] Don't raise your voice.
By the way, you want us to stop talking,
use your Spirit Gun. Come on.
Sheesh! Sure thing! Yeah, I'll shoot it.
Good, shoot. Go on. Do it.
- [whooshing]
- [straining]
[Spirit Gun powering up]
[panting]
[sighs]
Listen.
The only way you'll beat these monsters
is if you use the Spirit Gun.
Channel the energy inside,
and shoot it out of with all your heart.
Stop trying to shoot
with your fingers, all right?
[inhales deeply]
[sighing] Uh… All right. Once again.
- [Botan] Koenma.
- Do it!
- [Botan] Koenma!
- Huh?
[indistinct shouting]
[gasping]
[tense music playing]
[indistinct shouting continues]
- [man] Come on, son.
- [woman] What happened?
- [man] Are you okay? What happened?
- [woman] Help! Help!
[man] Hey, are you okay?
- [man] Are you okay?
- [woman] Mao, wake up.
- Hayato!
- Mao!
[man] Naoya! Naoya!
[machine beeping]
[Yusuke] Can't we get these kids
back to how they were?
[pensive music playing]
[Botan] Not if their souls
have been eaten.
That dangerous object.
Goki used it to do all this.
Is there anything I can do now?
Get their souls back from Goki.
It's the only way.
Well, that sounds easy enough.
I'll take him on right now.
What? That's a bad idea.
You haven't even got
your Spirit Gun working yet.
Forget that!
I don't need a Spirit Gun.
We get these kind of injuries
quite often, right?
- Yeah.
- Yeah, right! [laughing]
- You just want attention!
- [laughing]
You're in trouble now!
Tickle, tickle, tickle!
Hey, hey! Kuwabara, what's with his neck?
I'm sorry.
[breathing heavily] This is all my fault.
No.
Come on. Don't talk that way.
Thanks to you,
we got away with very little damage.
[breathing shakily]
I'm sorry.
Oh! Urameshi! Oh, hey, wait, wait.
- Kuwabara. Kuwabara.
- [Yusuke] Hey, Kuwabara. What's up?
You and I need to talk right now!
You beat up that guy. How'd you do it?
He was so strong too.
Guess that means it was a yokai
we were fighting, right?
- [Kuwabara] Yokai?
- Don't, don't!
So I drove the yokai out
with my Spirit Energy.
[shushing]
Hold on.
- Have you completely lost your mind?
- No, that's the truth.
[laughing] Okay.
- Did you get some meds yet?
- You think I'm crazy? Huh?
- Move it. Now!
- Ugh.
[Botan] Stop blabbering on
about the Spirit World and yokai!
[Kuwabara] Geez. Is he okay?
Why'd he bring that girl here?
[both laughing]
I didn't see her.
Huh? The kimono girl.
The one pulling Urameshi.
No.
He came here alone.
[mumbling]
Kuwabara, maybe you're seeing things!
[gasps] This is spooky!
- Scary.
[gasps, groans]
Maybe he's telling me the truth.
[friends muttering]
[intriguing music playing]
[Botan] Out of the three yokai thieves,
Goki is thought of as the most dangerous
in the Human World.
And that's because
Goki feeds off human souls.
His mere existence
is harmful to the human race.
[upbeat rock music playing]
Goki favors children's souls
in particular.
And the Rapacious Orb he has
will suck the soul out of you,
and keep them stocked up.
So, basically, the orb ended up
with the last person in the world
who should have it.
[Yusuke sighs]
Ugh, it's been a while since I've eaten
and we still haven't found anything.
Could be that he's
hiding his spiritual energy.
It's a little trick
that yokai in your world do.
[Yusuke] Are there many yokai
in the Human World?
No. But that wasn't always the case.
So we had to find a way to restore order.
Which was?
We decided to create a barrier
between our two worlds.
So, the stronger yokai are kept out
and your World then remains peaceful.
Yeah? And how about
that creature I killed?
Why was it able to cross over like that?
So, um…
- I don't--
- Well, what?
I don't know!
You're supposed to figure that one out!
Don't get so agitated. Let's go.
Hold on.
- Where are you going?
- [Yusuke] To get food.
Wait. How are you so relaxed?
Look, Botan. I'm not a tracking dog,
you understand that?
And do you really think
I can fight in this condition?
I need some food.
Planning ahead. But he's still an idiot.
- [Keiko] Oh, you see? He's here.
- [man] Welcome! Come on in.
- Hey!
- [Yusuke] Hey, kid.
Sir, thank you.
You're the reason I'm alive!
Nah, why so formal?
Sir, thank you for saving my son.
I really can't thank you enough.
[chuckling] Well, that's enough of that.
[chuckling] And they stopped by yesterday.
They wanted to thank you personally.
All right. All right.
Thanks, I guess. How are you?
Huh?
Mmm…
Well, it's just that…
[sighing] Actually,
a lot of children collapsed
right outside
our apartment complex recently.
So he's worried about that. Aren't you?
[tense music playing]
So this complex of yours,
where is it exactly?
[children] First comes rock. Rock, paper,
scissors, go! Again, again, again!
[children playing]
[girl] You're so funny! Whoa!
[children laughing]
- [man] Hey!
- [woman 1] Kazu!
- [woman 2] Hey, son!
- [woman 1] Haru!
- [woman 3] Kazuto!
- [woman 4] Are you okay?
[man] Are you messing with me?
Hey! Come on, get up! Come on!
- [woman 5] Hurry!
- [woman 3] What's going on?
- Kazu! Can you breathe?
- [man] What are you doing?
- [woman] Kazuto!
- [man] There he is!
[man 2] Wake up! Come on!
- [woman 1] Haru! [sobs]
- [man] Hey, can you hear me? Hey!
[suspenseful music continues]
[music intensifies]
[panting]
[pulsating]
And just who the hell are you?!
[grunting]
[coughs, grunts]
[growls]
Oh, I see. You're just an ordinary human!
[breathing shakily]
[roaring]
- [grunts]
- [growls]
[snarling]
[both grunting]
[Goki snarling]
[grunting]
[roaring]
[growling]
[intense music playing]
[panting]
[grunting]
- [glass shattering]
- [yelps]
[roaring]
[snarling]
[music intensifies]
[growling]
[snarling]
[Yusuke grunts]
[grunting]
- [Yusuke yells]
- [music slows down]
[music intensifies]
[growling, grunting continues]
[grunting]
[tires screeching]
[Yusuke yells]
[panting]
- [Goki growls]
- [loud thud]
[roars]
[grunts]
[growls]
[both grunting]
[growling]
[grunting]
[grunts, pants]
[exhales]
[growls]
[grunts]
[panting]
- [loud thud]
- [gasps]
- [Goki roaring]
- [panting]
[Goki roaring]
[roaring ferociously]
[grunts]
[Goki growling]
[Yusuke grunts, pants]
[grunting]
[roars]
[footsteps approaching]
[snarling]
[Yusuke panting]
[tense music playing]
[straining]
[Spirit Gun powering up]
[grunting continues]
[Goki snarling]
[breathing heavily]
[grunts]
[intense music playing]
[grunting]
- [grunts, growls]
- [Yusuke groans]
[grunts, pants]
[Goki snarling]
- [growling]
- [Yusuke grunting]
- [Yusuke choking]
- [growls]
[Masaru] Stop it!
[snarls]
Hey! You need to apologize.
[Yusuke choking]
You look like you'll be nice and tasty.
Masaru, run!
- [punch landing]
- [Yusuke groans]
- [grunts]
- [pulsating]
- Run away!
- Don't get in the way of my meal!
[intense music continues]
[grunting]
- [wind gusting]
- [pulsating]
[mystical tone]
[raspy breathing]
[grunts]
[continues pulsating]
[growling softly]
Stop it!
Quiet now.
[grunting]
Come on! This ends now!
[both grunting]
Let's go!
[growling]
[screaming]
- [loud explosion]
- [Goki yells]
[grunts]
- [grunting, panting]
- [dangerous object pulsating]
[Goki rasping]
[grunts, exhales]
[mystical tone]
[sighs]
[panting]
[uplifting music playing]
- Dear, are you awake? It's your mom!
- [man] Hey, are you all right?
- [woman sobbing] You're okay.
- [man] Can you get up? Huh?
- I'm so happy!
- [man] Are you okay now?
Thank you! Thank you!
[music continues]
[Masaru] Are you okay, big brother?
[chuckling]
Thanks for earlier.
[Masaru] Mm-hmm.
[Yusuke sighing]
All right.
Can you stand?
[Yusuke sighs]
Let's go home.
[banging]
[man] Hey, come on! Give me a break.
Come on now. Give us some tears.
[Tarukane] You lot are far too lax
with your ways!
[grunts]
If you want it to cry, you have to be…
[inhales sharply] …unrelenting.
[ominous music playing]
Mmm.
[girl crying]
[clinking]
[high-pitched ring]
[Tarukane gasps]
[laughs hysterically]
See! Look at that!
It's been a while
since we've had a Tear of Ice!
[laughs]
More tears. [laughs]
More tears now!
[mock crying hysterically]
[laughs maniacally]
Why are you staring at me?
All of your resistance is futile,
you monster!
[music continues]
It'll only get worse for you, understand?
[huffs]
[Tarukane] Damn him, that Sakyo.
That he would hand over such a faulty item
in exchange for that sinkhole.
- You!
- Yes!
I want you to get a good deal
on that Tear of Ice!
- Absolutely.
- Understand?!
Yes.
[man sighing]
[pensive music playing]
It'll be just a little while now.
I promise I'm gonna get you out of here.
But why?
I have a younger sister about your age.
[music continues]
[pulsating]
[inhales deeply]
[knife slicing]
[yelling]
[groaning]
[birds chirping]
[girl] Hello.
Oh, hello.
[Botan] Huh? Kurama was watching?
What was Kurama doing?
[Yusuke] Well, I told you,
he was just watching.
- He wasn't trying to help Goki either.
- Wh-- Whoa.
What he's playing at, I don't know.
But it was pretty sinister.
Kurama is a yokai in human skin.
An effective disguise.
He's also revealed almost nothing to us,
which means
he's quite the cunning adversary.
Plus, he is one of Goki's monsters.
And Kurama possesses
the Mirror of Darkness
which will grant him
whatever he desires, I'm afraid.
However evil the desire,
it will come true.
We can't let that happen.
Anything? Really?
Anything!
Natural disasters, mass killings…
You name it!
[Yusuke] Are you serious?
[Botan] The Mirror of Darkness reveals
its powers under a full moon.
We have to take it away
from him before then.
Yeah.
[Kuwabara gasps]
[gasps]
Whoa.
This won't light.
[rock music playing]
Wait.
Really?
Whoa.
Wha-- Huh…
- [woman 1] Thank you for waiting.
- [man] Come on in!
[woman 2] Welcome! Go ahead.
[indistinct chatter]
[ominous music playing]
[woman 3] Welcome! Yes, we have a table.
[indistinct chatter]
[Yusuke grunts]
Oh, hello. I… it's ready.
Just one moment please.
Thanks for coming, as always.
[ominous music continues]
[exhales]
[Botan] Koenma, I…
I think that this is…
Yes. Most likely Kurama's seen Yusuke.
It could be a trap.
[suspenseful music playing]
[crows cawing]
SARAYASHIKI GENERAL HOSPITAL
[birds chirping]
[suspenseful music continues]
[panting]
Don't worry.
Once I achieve my goal,
I'll return the Mirror of Darkness.
[woman] Shuichi?
You came?
- [grunts feebly]
- [Kurama sighs]
Hold on, Mom, you need to lie down.
[chuckles] It's okay.
I would like to greet your friend, son.
He travelled all this way
just to visit me.
[inhales deeply]
[sighs]
You two are friends?
[chuckles] I must look like
quite a sight to you.
But I'm glad you're here.
It's a relief.
You stopping by each day is
always a real treat, you know.
As your mother, it worries me
you don't get the chance to make friends.
[coughing]
- What's wrong?
- [continues coughing]
Easy. You in pain?
Just a minute. Just a minute.
[breathes deeply]
[coughing]
[breathing heavily]
[Kurama] Were you surprised?
[Yusuke] Yeah. I was.
Shuichi is the disguise I use
in the Human World.
And Shiori is my mother for now.
I've been deceiving that woman
for many years.
I don't understand.
Seventeen years back,
this creature attacked,
leaving me seriously injured.
So I hatched a plan.
To stay safe, I entered a fertilized egg.
My plan was to let her raise me.
I was going to move on
once I regained my strength.
You had a change of heart?
[sighs]
Do you think yokai
can feel something like compassion?
[Yusuke sighs]
[Kurama] I didn't think so either.
Then something changed when she fell ill.
[somber music playing]
They told me
she wouldn't last a month like this.
[Yusuke sighs]
[Kurama] So, I want to use this mirror…
to help my mom.
[pulsating]
[Kurama] That's my only wish.
Once that is done,
I will return the Mirror of Darkness.
Why are you telling me this?
I guess I just wanted someone
to hear my confession.
[chuckles softly]
And above all,
I think I can trust you.
[somber music continues]
[rustling]
Aw man.
[Botan sniffles]
I didn't realize his situation.
[sobbing]
His mother is dying.
Those two deserve to be happy.
That's going to be difficult.
Huh?
[doctor] Here we go.
This may sting a little.
- [man groaning]
- There.
[groaning continues]
[doctor] Let's continue.
A little bit more.
- [groaning]
- There. Good, good, good.
- [groans]
- [doctor] There. You're doing great.
- [whimpering]
- [doctor] Good, good, not much more.
[breathes deeply]
[doctor] Hang in there. We're almost done.
[inhales sharply]
[indistinct chatter]
- [man] Thank you!
- [Keiko] Thank you!
[woman] Thank you so much!!
- See ya.
- [woman] Please, come again.
Your noodles will get cold.
Hey, Keiko.
Hmm?
Yokai--
Or, it's just…
Is there good and bad
inside of everybody?
Wait. What are you asking now?
[Yusuke] Oh, it's just a thought.
Mmm…
I guess…
Oh! Like for example,
most people who don't know you very well,
they have the impression that you're
a bit of a rebel and a troublemaker.
I guess.
But I know you're not really like that.
[faucet running]
'Cause I judge people for myself.
I don't care if everyone else tells me
that someone is bad.
If someone seems good to me,
then I say they're good.
By the same token,
even if the whole world
thinks highly of someone,
if I think they're actually a jerk,
then they're a jerk.
And guess what?
I learned that from you, Yusuke.
What?
[laughs] Just kidding.
[customer] Keiko.
- Beer, please.
- All right!
[turns off faucet]
[gentle music playing]
[Botan] Yusuke! There's trouble!
What are you doing, Yusuke?
Let's go. Right now!
Come on, hurry! What are you doing?
I haven't even had my ramen yet.
What's the rush?
Because you need to hear this.
It's the Mirror. There's more to it
that Koenma didn't tell you.
Huh?
When you make a wish,
and the Mirror grants it,
it takes away something in return.
What something?
The life of the person making the wish.
[brooding music playing]
It's a full moon tonight,
so the Mirror of Darkness
will show its powers.
- We have to run.
- [Kuwabara] Urameshi!
What is it, Kuwabara?
Come on. You're joking, right?
Huh?
You're off to the hospital
to save that yokai. Isn't that right?
Hold on! How'd you know?
Didn't we see a yokai burn
someone's house down the other day?
Then you're under no obligation
to do anything for that guy.
[music intensifies]
Out of the way, Kuwabara.
Get back here now!
[panting]
[panting] Shit!
[monitor beeping]
[Mirror pulsating]
[music intensifies]
[pulsating]
[squelching]
[breathing heavily]
I wish…
for a good, long life for my mother.
- [whooshing]
- [Kurama grunting]
[breathing heavily]
- Shit!
- Urameshi!
[both panting]
[mystical whooshing]
- Damn it!
- Hey!
[grunting]
This is a trap! He's a yokai! He's lying!
It's my decision! Not yours! Let go!
- No way, you can't!
- [Yusuke grunts]
I won't let you die again.
Because I still haven't won against you.
Kuwabara.
[panting]
[whooshing]
Shit!
Urameshi!
[somber music playing]
[breathing shakily]
[Yusuke grunting]
[panting]
[Kurama] What are you doing?
I'm here to put an end to this!
Don't get in my way!
You know she's going to die
if I don't do this!
And if you die, your mother's
going to mourn you forever!
Take it from me. It's heartbreaking.
[somber music continues]
[Yusuke] There's no point
to all this if you die.
Hey, Mirror!
I'm gonna give you half my life too.
No, stop it!
- [loud bang]
- [both groaning]
[screaming]
[grunting]
[groaning]
- [Kuwabara] Urameshi!
- [breathing heavily]
Come on! Urameshi!
- Hey, Urameshi. [panting]
- [breathing shakily]
[Kuwabara] Hey, come on. Come on.
[Yusuke exhales]
[grunting softly]
[machine beeping]
Oh no.
Are you there?
[gentle music playing]
[breathing deeply]
[exhales]
Shuichi.
There you are, son.
[gentle music continues]
Mmm. [exhales]
I'm right here.
I'm not going anywhere.
Understand?
[Shiori grunts softly]
[gentle music continues]
[grunts]
[Yusuke exhales deeply]
Urameshi.
I'm sorry.
I was mistaken.
Earlier, I was…
about to have noodles.
[chuckles] Get me another.
[laughs]
Fine. All right.
[music fades]
[wind whooshing]
[thrilling music playing]
[music intensifies]
[music tempo slows]
[thrilling music continues]
- [grunts]
- [tires squealing]
[thrilling music continues]
- [groaning]
- [crackling]
[man shuddering]
[high-pitched ring]
[Tarukane] You're telling me
the Tear of Ice was stolen?
- [gasps, screams]
- [platter shattering]
[breathing heavily]
Well, who the hell stole it?!
Find out right now!
[man] From how it was done, sir,
it looks like it was the work of a yokai…
A yokai?
Shit!
Get Sakyo on the phone now!
[man] Yes, sir.
You son a bitch!
My good luck has been ruined
ever since our deal.
Those Tears of Ice I extracted
have caught the attention of a yokai!
I don't want to be involved
in any trouble. Hear me?
So I'm going to return Korime.
And you can forget
about the deal with the sinkhole.
[Sakyo on phone]
I'm very sorry for your inconvenience.
However,
your decision to void the contract
is far too hasty, Tarukane.
How so?
[Sakyo] How about this?
[intriguing music playing]
Please come over to my residence.
I'll get you
all the Tears of Ice you want.
I will also ensure
you're safe from the thieves.
Looking forward to your arrival.
[phone clicking]
[intriguing music continues]
Toguro,
I have a new job for you.
I hope you finally have one that's…
interesting.
[music fades]
[theme music playing]
[dramatic music playing]
[music ends]