[theme music playing]
[Enma] Yusuke, the Spirit Detective,
retrieved the Rapacious Orb from Goki.
Then, on learning of Kurama's wish…
[Yusuke] I'm going to
give you half my life too.
[Kurama] Stop it!
[Enma] He gave up half of his life
and recovered the Mirror of Darkness.
The only remaining dangerous object is
the Conjuring Blade,
currently in Hiei's possession.
[music ends]
[Enma] On being tasked
with retrieving this too,
Yusuke infiltrated a certain mansion.
[tense music playing]
Hey, Koenma.
You really think he's gonna show his face?
[Enma] The only people Hiei attacks
are subordinates of the jeweler.
So, it's likely he'll show up
and target the mansion's owner.
Hold on, you're saying you're not sure?
[Enma] That's why
you're investigating, idiot!
So shut up and focus
on retrieving the Conjuring Blade, yeah?
You're the boss.
You know, I should sue you
for harassment when this is over.
[Enma] Are you listening?
It's a dangerous object,
one that grants its wielder
their desired ability.
We don't know
what kind of power he's gained.
Be very careful
with how you proceed, got it?
Yeah, I got it.
- [gunshots]
- [gasps]
- [Botan] Ooh.
[guns firing]
- [man] Over there!
- [men yelling]
[laughs] How about that?!
My guess was as good as gold!
[both laugh]
You wanna medal?
[men grunting, whimpering]
- [man yelps]
- [gun firing]
- [gun clicks]
- [man whimpers]
I… I don't… I don't know!
The Korime isn't here anymore! I swear!
[Yusuke panting]
Hiei, yeah?
You're not the type to hand over the
Conjuring Blade without a fight, are you?
I know who sent you.
I'm not giving it to you.
[action music playing]
[grunts]
[groans]
[Yusuke] You bastard!
[yells]
[grunting]
[grunts]
[whizzing]
What a waste.
Even without drawing this sword,
I've beaten you.
[Yusuke breathing deeply]
[thrilling music playing]
[helicopter engine whirring]
[music intensifies]
[Sakyo] Tarukane, thank you
for coming all this way.
Sakyo!
A yokai is after us! There was an attack!
I'm sorry to hear that.
Well, you're safe now.
They're after that Korime. I know it.
What are you gonna do?
You don't have to worry.
I promise that you'll be safe
on this island.
- [man] Hey, I've got an interesting story.
- Here you go.
Yes, tell me! [laughs]
[man laughs] Oh, ho!
Well, if it isn't Tarukane!
You finally made it
into the club, have you?
- Huh?
- [chuckles]
Please. As you see, I offer
a kind of amusement for the wealthy
who have exhausted
their other indulgences.
[Tarukane] Well, I didn't come here
to play, Sakyo.
[Sakyo] I know.
But I think if you see this
with your own eyes,
you'll understand why
you should believe me.
[low growl]
[growling]
[suspenseful music playing]
[gasps]
What the hell are you doing?
It's a competition between two yokai.
[roaring]
[snarling]
[roaring ferociously]
[whirring]
Barely 30%, I guess.
[neck cracking]
[exciting music playing]
[whooshing]
[roaring]
[punch lands loudly]
[man] Ha! What a letdown!
You're gonna get taken down
that easy? Son of a bitch!
[laughing]
Well, you did bet on a long shot.
[laughs]
Toguro will be your new guard.
- Do you have a problem with that?
- [Tarukane] Not at all.
No.
So, now that I've gained your trust,
let's have the Korime moved
to a safe place.
Let's use this one here.
Get her inside.
[Tarukane] Wha--
[suspenseful music playing]
[tires screeching]
Hurry!
We'll use that chopper to leave!
No, wait. You'll be targeted
as well if you help me!
Right now, just worry
about yourself. All right?
[panting]
You know, what he said is right.
Self-preservation is
an important instinct.
- [man groans]
- [gasps]
- [grunts]
- [gun firing]
- [squeals]
[groaning, panting]
Well,
I suppose it doesn't matter
since you're going to die
very soon anyway.
[ominous music playing]
[whimpers, screams]
[high-pitched ringing]
[gasps] Good work!
Yes, very good!
Glad you're satisfied with our work.
Tell me about
these two characters right there.
[monitor beeps]
[Sakyo] It seems that one is human
and the other is a yokai.
They're dangerous.
To ensure your safe return…
I'll have them take care of you.
[thrilling music playing]
[music fades]
[people clamoring]
[Botan] People say,
"Taking candy from a baby,"
but if your enemy is too weak,
you won't want to take anything at all.
Well, anyway, there's no need
to be so down! Come on! Cheer up!
You're the reason I'm so depressed.
- Okay?
- [Botan] That's enough complaining.
Koenma wants you to meet someone
that can help your training.
Uh-- Seriously?
She's a renowned fighter
named Master Genkai.
She uses the Spirit Wave, which draws
on the human body's spiritual energy.
It'll be good for you because
you can't command Spirit Energy very well.
Huh?
Screw that. There's no way.
I can figure it out without her.
What I need to know is how to beat
that guy's speed. That's what.
All this carrying on.
Just shut up.
You need to start training now.
[Kuwabara]
Hold that conversation right there.
If you're training, then I'm coming along!
[both] Huh?
[upbeat song playing]
Hello, Genkai. [chuckling]
It's a great honor.
[Genkai] I was told
there would only be one student.
Uh, sor-- sorry, Master Genkai. It's just…
He sort of just tagged along.
Yes! [sighs]
Kazuma Kuwabara.
I look forward to training with you.
You have drive.
I would like to know the reason
you wish to train.
I think to learn the fighting spirit.
I must confess that I can't proudly
call myself this guy's rival yet.
[Yusuke] Hmm?
- Just who is whose rival now?
- Huh?
Son of a bitch.
How dare you ridicule
a man's strength and focus!
You're my rival? Come on!
There's no way in hell!
- Hey, stop it now.
- We've always been rivals!
- Knock it off, loser! Go back to school!
- [Kuwabara] We have always been rivals!
- [Yusuke] You're so full of it!
- [Kuwabara] When did we stop being rivals?
- [Yusuke] We never were!
- Silence!
- [echoing]
- [both grunt]
[both groan]
[Genkai] You are a noisy pair, aren't you?
Don't just loiter around,
come on and follow me.
The training is starting!
[both groaning]
[both] Yes!
[grunting]
[both breathing heavily]
[Botan] Hurry!
Let's go now!
[all panting]
[Yusuke] Shit!
- [Kuwabara yelling]
- [thudding]
[straining]
[whooshing]
[continues straining]
You are to hold this for 12 hours.
Are you crazy? [grunting]
[groaning]
[Genkai grunts, exhales]
[exhales] Impossible…
Delinquents these days.
You've got no grit, son!
Go take five and then we're starting over.
[Yusuke] Hey.
Just what is the point
of this training anyway?
[Genkai] No questions!
A fool like you
doesn't need to think about "meaning."
Just feel it with your body.
Then why not make the training useful
for a change?
I came here to get stronger. That's all.
[breathing heavily]
If you think my words are useless,
then very well.
All right. Attack now.
[breathes deeply]
You asked for it, you old bat!
[Yusuke grunting]
[Japanese combat music playing]
[grunting]
[grunts, pants]
[grunts]
[Genkai] You can't be popular
with the ladies.
You're far too impatient!
[clattering]
[grunting]
[gasps]
Your techniques lack control.
[grunting]
[grunts]
Shit!
[grunting]
That fighting style of yours,
are you trying to fight like Hiei?
[Yusuke grunting]
Challenging speed with speed?
An ill-advised strategy.
[breathing heavily]
[grunting]
[yells]
[grunts, coughs]
[grunting]
[yells]
[grunts]
[panting]
You can copy techniques that quickly?
[grunts]
- [exhales sharply]
- Here!
[Japanese combat music plays]
[gasps, grunts]
[groans]
[Genkai] Now don't go getting cocky.
Before you start complaining,
why not try practicing?
[breathing heavily]
Just what are you?
[birds chirping]
- [Kuwabara yelling]
- [thudding]
[grunting]
[exhales]
[yelling, grunting]
Kuwabara is supposed to break that rock
for his training.
With a wooden sword?
With a wooden sword.
[Kuwabara grunting]
Impossible. Clearly.
[Kuwabara] Damn it!
[yells]
[panting]
I ain't done yet!
[grunts]
[breathing deeply]
[yelling]
Another delinquent.
Unlike you, this one's got heart.
[Yusuke breathing heavily]
He will surpass you if you're not careful.
[Yusuke] Huh?!
Like hell he will!
- [Kuwabara grunting]
- [wooden sword thudding]
In that case,
you'd better get back to training now.
Your rest is long over, Yusuke!
[Yusuke] Ow, ow, ow! Let go, you old bat!
Come on, Yusuke!
[chuckles]
[pulsating]
[Kurama] Did you find your younger sister?
[sighs]
You opened the Jagan Eye?
I'm handling this alone.
That sword…
would you hand it over
since you're done with it?
What's that?
I'd like to give it
to that Spirit Detective.
Are you serious?
Mmm.
That's right.
In return maybe I can get information
from someone on her whereabouts.
Quit joking around.
Fraternizing with that kid…
[dramatic flourish playing]
[wind whistling]
[unsettling music playing]
[scientist] With this machine,
we have succeeded in generating
an enormous amount of energy.
However, with a chamber of this size,
all we can do is produce a hole
the size of a fist in the dimension.
[Sakyo] Then it's meaningless.
The hole needs to be bigger.
It's not that simple.
We'd require
another huge infusion of money.
[exhales]
I'll work something out.
I'll get you the money.
[pensive music playing]
Rare for you to stop by here.
Connecting the Human World
with the Demon World.
Do you think it'll work?
I honestly have no idea, but either way,
I'll continue to assist in your project.
I've just become too strong
for this world.
I need to go to the Demon World,
whatever it takes.
There's no one left to fight in this one.
TRAINING DAY 14
[straining]
[grunts, groans]
- How sad.
- [Yusuke pants]
You'll never beat Hiei
if you can't do this simple exercise.
Oh, quiet!
Didn't you say you wanted to get stronger?
[Yusuke grunts]
- [Yusuke] That's right.
- Why's that?
I need to get strong…
if I'm gonna beat Hiei.
[Genkai] What does it matter
if you can't beat him?
Huh?
Even if you give up your training,
it won't matter to anyone else.
Understand that if you don't fight,
many others can fight in your place.
I could.
Even that Kuwabara kid could do it.
[scoffs] No. You're wrong.
All this was the condition
for living again.
What "condition"?
You are mistaken, Yusuke,
if you believe you can defeat your enemy
with such a feeble resolve.
After all, do you really think
that Koenma would force you
back to the afterlife
if you quit your training?
Just a few things for you to consider.
[clicking tongue]
[door slides open]
[crickets chirping]
Ah! Hello, Genkai!
So, is Yusuke doing well?
[Genkai] He is utterly hopeless.
[exhales] Yes. That does sound right.
Tell Koenma that Yusuke
won't amount to anything.
[inhales sharply]
[gasps]
[sighs]
[whimsical music playing]
Kuwabara deciding to tag along
and train with Genkai was quite a shock.
Y-Yes…
Apologies, uh…
No worries.
Anyway, they've been training
for a while now.
Is Yusuke ready? Huh?
Mmm…
I think Yusuke's patience is
reaching a breaking point.
[music stops]
Huh?
[crickets chirping]
[lighter clicking]
Ah, shit!
- [Kuwabara grunting]
- [wooden sword thudding]
- [Kuwabara] Come on! [grunting]
[Kuwabara panting]
[Kuwabara grunting]
[Kuwabara] Son of a bitch!
[panting]
I can't believe he's still at it.
[yells]
[panting]
[Kuwabara] Shit!
[inhales deeply]
[yells]
[panting]
I can't lose anymore.
[pensive music playing]
[inaudible]
[breathing heavily]
[music continues]
[inhales sharply]
A man who can't protect
what's important to him
is no man at all.
[breathing heavily]
[inspirational music playing]
Hmm?
I'll become a stronger fighter
than that jerk! Just watch me!
[whooshes]
[rumbling]
[inspirational music continues]
[buzzing]
[exhales]
I did it.
Holy shit, I did it!
[music continues]
[music fades]
[chuckles]
TRAINING DAY 20
[birds chirping]
[pensive music playing]
[Yusuke breathing deeply]
[Genkai] Well, this is surprising.
He's been like that since last night.
He even said
that he'll beat Kuwabara, just you wait.
Yes. Fascinating.
[grunts]
[motivational music playing]
[Genkai] I see determination on your face.
[scoffs] That right?
Come on outside.
[Botan] Hey! Hey!
Your Spirit Energy has grown
since you started.
I can feel that your heart is strong.
Your foolish competitive streak
is what did it.
Why is it foolish?
It's foolish because
you're still wasting energy.
Like a hose that's been
left running, full of water…
You can condense your Spirit Energy
if you squeeze the end of the hose.
Now practice.
More crazy instructions today.
It's not crazy.
There's a reason
that I had you stand on that spike.
It was preparation for this.
I see.
[thrilling music playing]
[energy whooshing]
[wind whooshing]
Such strong energy!
Yusuke!
Almost there now!
[exhales]
Let's do this.
[energy whooshing]
[energy fires]
[epic music playing]
[music ends]
[sinister music playing]
I haven't seen that expression a while.
Extraordinary.
Something quite interesting is near.
[laughing]
[birds calling]
[ominous music playing]
[music fades]
They know.
[tense music playing]
[breathing shakily]
[grunting]
[Yusuke exhales]
[grunts softly]
Master, what's wrong?
[Genkai] Yusuke.
I'm going to give you something.
That desire to grow stronger.
Do you still feel it?
Yeah.
I feel it all the time.
Well, then I'm sure you'll become
even stronger in the future.
As you get older your skills will improve.
Your tactics will mature also.
And yet, all of us are aware
that the day will arrive
when we can no longer resist
the power in front of us.
And I've learned to accept that fact.
Living with the flow
and dying.
We have to entrust our hopes
to the next generation.
[Yusuke scoffs]
Is this another lesson?
[Genkai] Just be quiet and listen.
You must understand that sacrificing
what you value to gain power
is not real strength.
In reality, it is weakness of heart.
Remember that.
Now will you carry this wisdom with you?
[inspirational music playing]
In all honesty…
before all this started,
I don't think I would.
Something did occur to me, though.
The world is counting on us to do this.
As long as I'm alive,
I will honor their trust.
Yusuke, hear me,
don't ever forget those words.
[music continues]
[Genkai] This is the Spirit Wave Orb.
It's yours.
And you will carry it
inside of you as your secret.
Take it.
[inspirational music continues]
[music intensifies]
[music fades]
The world needs you now more than ever.
Your training is hereby complete.
You may leave this mountain.
[dramatic music playing]
We'll return for training soon!
Even if you're against it, all right?
You two take care.
[chuckles]
[Kuwabara] Okay!
[music ends]
[sighs]
[wind whooshing]
[thunder rumbling]
[ethereal music playing]
[door sliding open]
[thunder crashing]
[tense music playing]
You've aged, Genkai.
Looks like the years
have been kind to you.
Just as I remember you 50 years ago.
You gave the Orb to that kid already?
Yes.
Then I sent him on his way. He's not here.
In that case, I've no further use for you.
No. [scoffs]
Really, I can't bear to look at you
in your current state.
[thunder rumbling]
As this old woman.
A truly depressing end.
The feeling's mutual, I assure you.
So pathetic, selling your soul.
And just because you want
to cling to your fleeting strength.
Then I'm afraid
that one of us will have to go away.
[inhales deeply]
Well, you haven't changed, have you?
You still care about fighting,
and nothing else at all.
[thunder crashing]
[straining]
[grunting]
Mmm. [slurping]
[Keiko] Hey, here I am!
- [woman] Welcome home.
- [man] Welcome home.
Ugh. Yusuke, where have you been?
What's going on?
Uh, Kuwabara and I
were at a training camp.
Are you serious?
What do you mean training?
You two are always fighting.
So what? There's a lot going on.
[man] Keiko, please take the curtain down.
Got it.
[slurps, gulps]
Phew! That was good!
[clears throat] All right. I'm out!
- [woman] Thank you, Yusuke!
- [man] Thank you. See you!
[Keiko] I think it's great
that you guys get along now.
It's not like that. Got it?
[Keiko] Huh? I don't get it.
All right. See ya!
You do need to go back
to school eventually, you know?
Yeah, yeah.
[curtain rod clatters]
[dramatic music playing]
[Yusuke] You bastard!
Hey! Keiko!
Get back here!
[panting]
- See ya later.
- Mmm.
[chuckles]
Just be careful.
- Okay.
- [laughs]
[rapid footsteps approaching]
[panting] Kuwabara! Yusuke needs you!
- Huh?
- [Botan] Keiko's been kidnapped!
[music intensifies]
[rapid footsteps approaching]
[panting]
[dramatic flourish playing]
You're back again?
Where did you take her?!
- [action music playing]
- [grunting]
[grunts]
[panting]
[music fades]
[thrilling music playing]
[grunting]
[grunting, groaning]
[grunts]
[yells]
[Hiei] That power…
- [Keiko] Let me go!
- [man] Hold still!
- [Keiko] Let go!
- [man] I said, hold still!
Hey!
[Keiko grunting]
[Keiko panting]
You're a feisty one, aren't you?
- [grunts]
- [man] Get back here!
- [Keiko grunts]
- [Hiei whines]
[ominous music playing]
[laughs]
[gasps]
[chuckles, grunts]
[groans]
Ooh.
[whimpers]
[laughing maniacally]
- [thrilling music playing]
- [grunting]
[yelling]
[grunts]
[breathing heavily]
[thrilling music continues]
- [Yusuke yells]
- [Hiei grunts]
[sword swishing]
[energy whooshing]
[Yusuke grunting]
[Yusuke] Give Keiko back.
Who the hell is Keiko?
You know who she is, asshole!
[gasps]
[breathing heavily]
[footsteps approaching]
[Kurama] The two of you
shouldn't be fighting.
Kurama?
Don't get in my way!
He wasn't the one who took your friend.
Yeah, like hell.
I saw you kidnap her.
You two have fun together.
I found out where your sister is.
[pensive music playing]
[low growl]
- [computer beeps]
- [door opens]
This is what you found so interesting?
Yes.
For my brother's sake,
I thought I'd make it
a real welcome party.
Well then,
we'll extend a cordial invitation.
[Yusuke] So you're telling me
that Keiko and his younger sister
are being held hostage in the same place?
Looks like it.
What could be the reason?
I have some idea
why Hiei's younger sister was kidnapped.
That said,
I'm not sure
why your girlfriend was taken.
She's not my girlfriend.
Does it matter?
Huh? How about you shut it?
Hey, listen to me.
It's likely that we're playing right
into their hands if we rush in there.
This is far too well orchestrated
if all they wanted was her.
That's just fine.
If we act on their invitation,
it'll lead us to Keiko.
[sighs]
Lead the way.
[Hiei sighs]
Hiei.
Sorry, I shouldn't have
attacked you earlier.
Let's go together.
Come on. Let's get your sister.
[Hiei sighs]
[Kurama] I'll take you
to Kubikukuri Island.
[sinister music playing]
Urameshi!
[Yusuke] Kuwabara?
You bastard!
You trying to keep me out of this?
You're gonna save Yukimura, right?
- Yeah.
- Well, then I'm going too, obviously.
[Hiei] Who the hell are you?
You wanna die?
Say that again.
I think a little guy like you
should learn to keep his mouth shut.
[Yusuke] Hey, cut it out.
Hiei's with us.
No, I'm not.
'Course you're not, jackass.
I'm not gonna partner
with an idiot like you.
You bastard!
Wow, this asshole sure knows how
to make a first impression!
[man] We've been expecting you.
The boss has requested that
I invite you all to Kubikukuri Island.
[thrilling music playing]
[music ends]
[thunder rumbling]
[ominous music playing]
[Toguro sighs]
[music intensifies]
[thunder rumbling]
[thunder crashing]
[theme music playing]
[dramatic music playing]
[music ends]